Are you comfortably seated in front of the TV?
Are you ready for a real Christmas story?
Okay.
Once upon a time
there was a carpenter and his wife.
His name was Joseph.
And hers was Mary.
They traveled to the city of Bethlehem, -
- because the emperor in Rome said
that everyone in his kingdom should be counted.
Mary was very pregnant.
on her pillow thoughts stand in line
planted in the earth like flower seeds
shoots and sprouts and twists around
she understands nothing at all
hours feel like days
and weeks a thousand years
came to look back
to a world of yesterday
Jesus and Josefine
homeless heartache
but Jesus makes Josefine
believe in miracles
when she wavers
Jesus and Josefine
faithless time machine
the tempter's concubine
she needs miracles
when she wavers
(Mary groans)
We'll make it, Mary. I'll find a place.
- It has to be now.
- Pray to God that he waits a little.
- God wants me to give birth now.
- Here it is.
I knew it.
I knew it was right here.
(knocks)
My wife is giving birth.
We're from Nazareth.
Everything is full.
Everything is full in Bethlehem.
Now it's not my problem
that the whole world has to be entered in the census.
(Mary whimpers)
- You can borrow my stable.
- My son shall not be born in a stable.
Yes, it has to be now, Joseph.
(Mary gasps)
(baby cries)
- I think he should be named Joseph.
- No, he shall be named Jesus.
The angel said so himself.
But Joseph sounds
at least just as good as Jesus.
(knocks)
An angel said
we should find the baby Jesus.
- Is this it?
— Yes.
Right, Joseph?
(church bells ring)
Josefine, wake up.
- Josefine, it's the first of December.
- I don't feel like it.
Look what I got.
An advent calendar.
- Don't you have enough elf hats?
- You're grumpy because you don't have one.
Lukas, I don't want one this year.
- You can have a gift from me.
- I don't want it.
No, Lukas, stop.
Lukas, it's forbidden
to have elf hats on my side.
Okay.
(egg timer rings)
- Now there are first-of-December buns.
- How nice they are. It's a miracle.
- They're neither burnt nor anything.
- I didn't look at the recipe.
Who's ready to crack a tooth
on dad's Christmas buns?
- Is there rice pudding in them?
- You don't put that in buns.
There is actually
a little bit of rice pudding in them.
They taste super good.
Now there's just the thing,
that Christmas has been cancelled.
- That's not true, is it?
- Christmas has been moved to Midsummer.
Then I get my birthday to myself.
And your calendar gift doesn't count anymore.
- That's not true, right?
- No, of course not.
Christmas is the children's festival.
And then we celebrate Jesus' birthday.
- Just because you've just become a priest.
- Now I don't know much about Jesus.
But as a schoolteacher, I would know
if Christmas had been moved.
You don't know anything about that,
because you're on leave.
I know exactly what Christmas is.
It's right here.
- I'm holding on to it.
- You have a bad back.
Yeah yeah. Now put some fir in your hair.
It's unfair,
that I have my birthday on Christmas Eve.
I couldn't hold you back.
Last year we sang happy birthday
around the Christmas tree. That was nice.
No one.
You could also say it's cool to have
your birthday the same day as Jesus.
Yeah, enormously cool.
We've offered you that you could
celebrate your birthday another day.
And if you want to invite
your friends home for Christmas …
I don't want to share my birthday with someone
who lived over 2,000 years ago.
- You shouldn't talk about Jesus like that.
- Dad says he maybe didn't exist.
Dad says so much. But no matter what,
Jesus is an incredibly important person.
- I'm also an important person.
— Yes.
You are very important to dad and to me
and to Lukas and your friends.
So what's the problem with
moving Christmas?
Listen. I'm having a busy month
with funerals and christenings, -
- and I have to hold the Christmas service
at 9,
so I really can't handle problems.
But I promise you,
you'll have a good birthday.
Can we celebrate your birthday in the
morning and do a little Christmas in the evening?
(mobile phone rings)
Hi, Oskar. I can only have
birthday in the morning, -
- because Jesus is
much more important than me.
I probably didn't say it
quite like that.
Okay, I'll come over.
- Hi, Oskar.
- Hi.
- Has Stella given birth?
- No, my mom says it'll happen today.
Hi, little Stella.
Belly full of pups.
Actually, I just came
to say goodbye.
- Why do you have to say goodbye?
- I'm leaving here in December.
- May I come with you?
- Yes, but we don't celebrate Christmas Eve.
Christmas is totally forbidden.
But in return, there's Josefine Eve.
Then it'll be without me.
I love Christmas Eve.
But you know that today
we're assigning roles for the nativity play.
I thought that we two
could play Joseph and Mary.
I have a much better idea.
We're going to play the donkey.
The donkey?
We're going to rehearse those roles for
almost a month.
(the phone rings)
That was probably the shepherds
and the holy three kings.
Yes, and we're still missing
King Herod and his helper.
We're missing Joseph and Mary and …
Oh yes, the donkey. Is there anyone
who voluntarily wants to play the donkey?
There's Josefine and Pia and Nina.
We only need two.
- Me and Oskar, we want to.
- I'm not playing the donkey.
Then it'll be Pia and Nina.
You'll be the donkey.
I want to play Herod.
Then Oskar can be my helper.
- Why do you want to play King Herod?
- Because I don't like Jesus.
- Why don't you like him?
- He stole my birthday.
- (everyone sighs in exasperation)
- Yes, Emilie,
Can we skip hearing about
that birthday this year?
I think Josefine would benefit from
playing someone who likes Jesus.
- I think you should play Mary.
- No, really?
- And then Oskar can play Joseph.
- Okay.
And then Emilie can be King Herod.
And, Christina, you can be
King Herod's helper.
And I've allowed myself
to take the role of the angel.
And now look.
Here is old Palestine.
Now, for the next 24 days, we're going to take
a really exciting journey right here.
It was a country
marked by a lot of unrest.
It was a Jewish land
occupied by the Romans.
Look, here is Bethlehem, -
- where Jesus was born.
And here is Nazareth,
where he grew up.
Yes, Josefine?
What if we make the stable so dirty
that Jesus gets sick and dies?
If Jesus had died as an infant,
we wouldn't have gotten to know him.
- And then what?
- Then God couldn't have forgiven us.
And we never would have learned
to forgive each other.
And your mom wouldn't have become a priest.
And we couldn't have done
a nativity play in any church.
Then I could have
my birthday in peace.
Is there really nothing
about Christmas that you like?
When it's over.
- That's fine, you should play Maria.
- Do you really think so?
The Virgin Mary is
an incredibly strong female role.
I just have to sit and say:
"Oh, how sweet he is.
The best child in the world."
They made such
sweet and well-behaved children in Biblical times.
- I want to do a nativity play too.
- Come here.
What do you say to "Jesper's Baking Bible"?
- What are you talking about?
- I want to make a cookbook.
With all the world's Christmas pastries.
- You don't use recipes anyway.
- That's because they're way too difficult.
I want to make simple recipes
that people can understand.
It's about using your common sense.
Then you can bake.
That should be the message of the book.
I think it'll be a huge success.
What about that time you wanted to make
a children's book? Did you get to page 7?
I couldn't figure out
what it should end with.
A cookbook is more me.
Try to support me for once.
Of course we'll support you.
Jesper's Baking Bible is a fucking great idea.
- Let's see if you finish it.
- Of course I will.
(cell phone rings)
- Hi, Oskar.
- You have to help me. Stella is gone.
- I'm coming over.
- Okay.
Stella?
Hi.
I thought it was down there just now.
(dog barks)
- We'd better go out and look.
- Is it these you're looking for?
Hi.
I just found them behind a container.
Then I put them here in the box.
How cute they are.
- What are they?
- Dogoer.
Dogoer?
- Thank you so much.
- You're welcome.
I was passing by anyway.
Bye bye.
Look how small they are.
He was pretty weird.
- Why do you think so?
- I just do.
(wind whooshes)
Dear God, if you exist.
Can't you promise me
to take good care of Oskar's little Dogoer?
And if you really exist,
can you do me that favor -
— to move Christmas to
a different date than December 24th?
- Mom says you can't.
- Lukas.
I can't handle another year, -
- where I can't have
my birthday in peace. Amen.
(door creaks)
Is anyone there?
- It was just a sandstorm.
- I dreamed someone took him from me.
No one would dream of
stealing a little child.
You know perfectly well Jesus is not
just any ordinary child.
We must take good care of him.
For tonight a savior is born.