Are you comfortably seated in front of the TV?
Are you ready for a real Christmas story?
Okay …
It's unfair,
I have my birthday on Christmas Eve.
12-year-old Josefine doesn't think it's
fun to have her birthday on Christmas Eve.
Last year we sang
happy birthday around the Christmas tree.
And the year before we had
a class party, and who came?
No one.
If only she could find
a way to move Christmas.
It's hard when Christmas is Jesus'
birthday, and your mom is a priest.
It can also be cool to have
your birthday the same day as Jesus.
That doesn't make it easier
that they have to rehearse a nativity play, -
- and Josefine is forced to
play the Virgin Mary.
Her best friend,
classmate Oskar, -
- has a shed in his backyard.
Here he has a cage with
small degus from South America.
Hi, Oskar.
One of the degus is named Stella,
and she can give birth any time.
In the evening, Stella disappears.
You have to help me. Stella is gone.
Josefine helps with the search.
But a mysterious man
beats them to it.
Is it these you're looking for?
Hi.
What was that mysterious guy
doing in front of the stable, -
- where the baby Jesus was born
2,000 years ago?
on her pillow thoughts queue up
planted in the ground like flower seeds
shoots and sprouts and winds around
she understands nothing at all
hours feel like days
and weeks a thousand years
came to look back
to a world of yesterday
Jesus and Josefine
homeless heartache
but Jesus gets Josefine
to believe in miracles
when she wavers
Jesus and Josefine
faithless time machine
the tempter's concubine
she needs miracles
when she wavers
(knock on the door)
Your Royal Highness Herod.
Three wise men from the East.
Your High Excellency,
where is the newborn king of the Jews?
We have seen his star rise,
and we have come to worship him.
But now we are lost,
so we come to you.
We bring gold, frankincense, and myrrh.
- We want to kneel at the new king's feet.
- Well, then kneel.
- He's right here.
- Sorry?
Yes, he's certainly not a newborn.
But he will be the new king
when I die.
His name is Herod, just like mine.
(clinking)
Joshua, our high priest.
Step closer. Yes, he is blind.
But he sees more than most.
It is written
in the old scriptures, -
- that a ruler shall be born in Bethlehem.
And he will shepherd Israel's people.
A ruler shall be born in Bethlehem,
you say?
And it's not my son?
That must be the answer to your question.
Go to Bethlehem, my lords.
Find the new king, and …
… when you have found him,
come back to me, -
- so that I may worship him
with you.
(laughs maliciously)
You have such small, fine hands.
These are real king's hands.
They are not king's hands, Maria.
These are a good set of carpenter's hands.
- Is that the king?
- I'm a carpenter.
May we see?
Peace, little king.
- Such small hands he has.
- Real king's hands.
Peace be with you.
Yes, sorry.
We forget to introduce ourselves.
I am Caspar. Melchior. And Balthazar.
We have brought gifts.
"Oh, wise men. I thank you
for giving my child gifts."
"Oh God …"
"I thank God because He let you see
the great star in the heavens."
I think you'll be
a super good Virgin Mary.
I think it sounds completely right
when you say it.
I don't think
Virgin Mary spoke like that.
Do you perhaps know
how she spoke 2,000 years ago?
I think Josefine is right.
No one knows how people talked.
- Then I'll just rewrite it.
- We don't know much about them.
Except that it's believed
Jesus was born in the summer.
In the summer?
- Jesper, watch your cookbook.
- I am too.
There are some Christmas pretzels here
that you should taste.
They should be the second recipe in:
"Jesper's Cookbook.
24 really simple Christmas recipes."
Should there only be 24 recipes in it?
Yes, then there should be some pictures
and something about the history of bread.
You can also settle for four recipes.
Then there's a greater chance
that you'll finish it.
If Jesus was born in the summer, -
- why do people celebrate him
on my birthday?
That was something the church decided,
right, Louise?
- Jesus was born on Christmas Eve.
- That's actually right.
Jesus was born on Christmas Eve,
and you can't change that.
I believe in Jesus and in Santa Claus.
- Cut it out.
- That's my calendar gift.
So, you two. Pine needles in your hair.
Who should I write to?
I'd try the Ministry of Church Affairs.
So I'll write and ask to have
Christmas moved to Midsummer.
Yeah, here you go.
My prince, we bring you gifts.
Gold, frankincense and myrrh pure.
Phew, it's hot here. Probably because
it's the middle of summer.
That doesn't say so in the script.
Jesus was thus born
in the middle of summer.
— Jesus was born on Christmas Eve.
- Don't I have it right, Jytte?
No. We'll take it again.
I thank you for wanting to be in
our humble stable here in Bethlehem.
What do you say to watching Jesus
while we party it up in Jerusalem?
- Try to see what it says there.
- "Christmas-free zone"?
That must be just the thing for me. Come on.
(doorbell rings)
Can you see who it is?
It's that mysterious guy from yesterday.
- Hi, mysterious from yesterday.
- Hello. My name is now Thorsen.
Oh, is that you?
How are the goats doing?
- They're doing fine, right, Oskar?
- Yes, they're doing well.
— We just wanted to say thanks for the help.
- No problem. I was just passing by.
- May we look around a bit?
- Yes yes, anything you like.
Josefine, I do have
an appointment with my mom.
No, we can definitely find
a lot for the nativity play.
- I'm going home now.
- Okay.
- See you,
- See you, Oskar.
Bye bye.
- Does all this cost only one krone?
- Yes, well …
- Is there something special you're looking for?
- No, I'm just looking.
Why is it a Christmas-free zone?
Yeah, that … I don't care
much about Christmas.
- Does it bother you?
- No, I think it's cool.
Why's that, if I may ask?
Because I have my birthday on Christmas Eve,
and it's really annoying.
You have to put up with a lot, huh?
Sometimes even too much.
Yeah,
- It was nice to meet you.
- Likewise, Josefine.
- You're always welcome.
- Thanks.
- Is "Ministry of Church Affairs" spelled with a capital?
- Hold on a little break.
We're going to eat now.
- Why do we have to have rice pudding?
- I promised Lukas.
— I'm a gnome.
- When you were little, you loved it.
- Sorry, I've gotten big.
- But I do like rice pudding.
- It looks really delicious.
- I've kept it simple.
Can't I have something else to drink?
Maybe apple juice.
You can only drink elf beer
with rice pudding.
- You don't decide that.
- That's quite right.
There you hear it yourself.
Oh hell!
- He didn't do it on purpose.
- Yes, he did.
Josefine!
If you're really quick,
you can make it down and buy a new spoon.
(doorbell rings)
Hello?
Can I buy a pot ladle for a krone?
Hello? Is anyone here?
(cat meows in the distance)
(chimes start)
(doorbell rings)
Well?
- What can I do for you?
- You don't have an old pot ladle?
An old pot ladle?
That's not what I sell the most of.
I wonder if there might be
a couple left?
Are you going to make porridge?
Should it be very worn
or only a little worn?
- The price is the same.
- I think it should be very worn.
This one? Is it worn enough?
Yes, thanks.
Why is it actually
that you don't like Christmas?
You'd like to know?
Good. To make
a long story very short…
This boy could well be me.
I've stood alone in the snow on Christmas Eve,-
- because I'd said
something naughty to my dad.
He threw me out.
And there I stood. Completely alone.
I had to wrap old newspapers around my legs
and sleep in a cold stairwell.
Yeah….
Since then I've refused
to celebrate Christmas.
- Here you go.
- Thanks. Bye.
Bye.
Here you go. And sorry.
You took quite a while.
- How's the letter coming?
- I'm almost done.
- Can't we hear a bit?
- Yes.
"Dear Church Ministry.
We are quite a few,-
- who think it's strange
that Christmas Eve is December 24th,-
- when it's proven that Jesus
was born in the summer."
Therefore I suggest
we move Christmas Eve to Midsummer,-
- and it can happen pretty quickly."
Best regards, Josefine,"
- That's a stupid letter.
- Yeah yeah, eat your rice pudding.
Dear God, or whoever is out there.
I wouldn't mind,
if there were Christmas-free zones everywhere.
- What kind of Lone?
- Lukas, good night.
(door creaks)