Are you comfortably seated in front of the TV?
Are you ready for a real Christmas story?
12-year-old Josefine doesn't think it's
fun to have her birthday on Christmas Eve.
If only she could find
a way to move Christmas.
But it's hard when Christmas is Jesus'
birthday, and your mom is a priest.
Is "Kirkeministeriet" spelled with a capital?
Josefine and Oskar have found out that
the mysterious man has a shop.
- Hi, mysterious from yesterday.
- Hello. My name is now Thorsen.
Thorsen doesn't like Christmas either.
- Does that bother you?
- No, that's cool.
Josefine goes exploring
in Thorsen's shop.
Maybe it holds
an exciting secret.
on her pillow thoughts stand in line
laid in the ground like flower seeds
shoots and sprouts and winds around
she understands nothing at all
hours feel like days
and weeks a thousand years
came to look back
to a world of yesterday
Jesus and Josefine
homeless heartache
but Jesus makes Josefine
believe in miracles
when she wavers
Jesus and Josefine
faithless time machine
tempter's concubine
she needs miracles
when she wavers
(Maria hums softly)
(heavy boot steps)
Any news about the child in Bethlehem?
The three wise men found what they sought,
and took another way home.
We don't know where the child is.
So it's true.
The Savior is born.
He who shall be king over us all,
King over us all?!
Never.
I hereby command:
All male children under two years
in Bethlehem shall be killed.
The Savior must not die.
What about the innocent children?
Begone.
You are no longer my high priest.
But the children!
The innocent children. The children!
Get on with it.
(sheep bleat)
This stable could become
a fantastic carpenter's workshop.
The owner wants to sell. We just need
the gold from the wise men.
Joseph, my son shall not grow up
in a stable in Bethlehem.
That is also My son.
(door creaks)
Rise, Joseph of Nazareth.
Take the child and its mother
and flee to Egypt.
— Stay there until I tell you.
- To Egypt?
King Herod has sent out riders.
He wants to kill the child.
Kill Jesus? But why?
- We must leave immediately.
- What about my carpenter's workshop?
- Then I'll go alone.
- No, Mary. I understand.
We're leaving right away.
- What now?
- I want to take the manger with us.
- Not when we're fleeing.
- It's a reminder of Jesus' birth.
It shall stay with me,
as long as I live.
(sighs)
"Oh, my beautiful wife.
We are traveling to the land of Egypt."
"What joy
that the angels came and warned us."
"One can always trust God in Heaven."
How beautiful. I'm touched.
You really fit well together.
- Don't you think it's nonsense?
- What do you mean?
That the virgin Mary had a child with God.
The Bible says that Mary
became pregnant with the Holy Spirit, -
- and the Holy Spirit is part of God.
Don't you think Mary fooled around
with some other guy besides Joseph?
I don't think so.
I'm a priest, after all.
- But you're a modern priest.
- What do you mean by "modern"?
One who doesn't believe everything in the Bible.
I believe everything
that one can learn from the Bible.
What actually happened
doesn't interest me.
- But of course I believe.
- I believe in the Holy Spirit.
- I believe in Santa Claus.
- And sweet treats and spruce in the hair.
Spelt bun? There's honey in it,
and then there are birches around.
What do you think?
- They taste pretty good.
- I'm making a cookbook.
It will be called "Jesper's Cookbook".
This will be recipe number three.
- Don't you think it'll be a hit?
- That's not my dad. Let's go.
And then King Herod ordered, -
— that all boys
under two years old should be killed.
How could Herod do something
so evil?
I think that Herod
was maybe jealous of Jesus.
And when one is jealous, the Devil
can make one do the strangest things.
Just like Josefine.
Jytte, if you're going to be completely honest,
do you think Jesus was God's son?
Yes, of course Jesus was God's son.
How do you know?
Because once
I was visited by an angel, -
- who told me
that it all is true.
Yeah, okay.
(bell rings)
Before you go, let's find out, -
- who provides
the props and costumes.
We need both some shepherd's staffs
and some carpenter's tools for Joseph.
And robes. Is there anyone
who's good at sewing?
I actually think
I can get it all.
- We know a shop.
- We're not going back there.
Yes, and you have to help carry.
(doorbell rings)
Hey, Josefine and Oskar. Hi.
We need props for
our nativity play. Can we look around?
Yes, yes. Anything you feel like.
It's desire that drives the work.
And I most feel like sitting
and cozying up with this book.
- It's creepy here.
- You can be scary yourself.
Try looking around.
Try seeing those there.
Shepherd's staffs.
"Oh, see the big star.
It shines so brightly."
Try seeing this one.
Joseph can use that
when he works in his workshop.
Try seeing here. Here are some robes.
Oskar, I want to show you
something totally wild. Come on.
Where is Jesus?
What do you say then?
Josefine,
There's something I've been thinking about.
Us two.
- Looks good.
- Are you finding anything you can use?
I didn't know
you liked Christmas stuff.
Just that nativity play
I refuse to throw out.
It's not for sale either.
Look here, I just found this one.
Wasn't that something
your Herod could use?
I think Emilie will love that one.
Thorsen, if you're going to be
completely honest, -
- do you think Jesus is God's son?
Yes, maybe.
But isn't it irrelevant?
- Why is it irrelevant?
- Aren't we all gods?
We're humans, not gods.
If we were all gods,
what's the fun in that?
Yeah, the fun is
that then we're invincible.
And have the right to do whatever we want.
Stella? Come on, Stella.
What about you, Stella? Are you a god too?
I think that thing about
us all being gods is nonsense.
I think it sounds cool.
Do you want something to eat, Stella?
Josefine, there's something
I want to ask you.
I'm going home now.
It's important,
and you need to sit down.
- Josefine?
- Yes, Oskar?
You promise to come over and help
carry this to school tomorrow.
There's also something else,
I want to ask you about.
Do you want to …
- I said it should go quickly.
- Josefine, wait a bit.
Would you like to get together?
Oskar, we are friends, after all.
Being boyfriend and girlfriend is also
a kind of being friends.
I'd like to think about it a bit.
Is there a whole kilo of pepper in it?
- No, just a teaspoonful.
- Aw.
- Spruce in the hair.
- What does that mean?
It means you have to put
some spruce in your hair, -
- then you get in the Christmas mood.
Like this.
What are you thinking about?
Nothing.
- I can tell you're thinking about something.
- It's private.
- Is it something with Oskar?
- No, why do you think that?
- I don't know.
- What are you writing?
It's not very private.
I'm writing my sermon.
Can't you just write that we
don't know if Jesus was God's son?
People would probably be disappointed.
Besides, it's not true.
Do you dare sign under
that Jesus was God's son?
I can sign it,
but deep down I don't really know.
- So you're standing there lying in church?
- No.
I can stand by what Jesus says.
That we should be kind to each other
and accept that we're different.
Doesn't it smell burnt here?
No no no.
- Shall we play Kalaha?
- In a bit.
(Josefine types away)
- I have just as many as you.
- Not anymore.
Then I get to take all yours.
- You didn't know that one.
— Bullshit.
We can play again tomorrow.
Josefine?
- What have you written in my sermon?
- What do you mean?
"But that Jesus was God's son,
I don't believe, -
- and aren't we all gods?"
And then you suggest
that Christmas should be moved to Midsummer.
I can't stand in church
on Sunday and say something like that.
- Why not?
- Because it's nonsense.
And if I did say it,
I'd get fired.
Oh
ah
- Goodnight, kids.
- Goodnight, mom.
Dear God,
or should I say co-god?
If you're up there somewhere,
won't you make it so that, -
- Oskar doesn't get too sad?
Because tomorrow I have to tell him,
that I don't want to be girlfriend.
Are you the worst?
No, that's you, if you don't
lie down and sleep now.
Amen.
(carillon)