Are you sitting comfortably in front of the TV?
Are you ready for a real Christmas story?
"What fortune
that the angels came and warned us."
12-year-old Josefine doesn't think it's
fun to have her birthday on Christmas Eve.
If only she could find
a way to move Christmas.
But it's hard when Christmas is Jesus'
birthday, and your mom is a priest.
Don't you think Mary fooled around
with some other guy besides Joseph?
- I'm a priest, after all.
- But you're a modern priest.
In Thorsen's shop, they find all sorts of things
they can use for the nativity play.
Tunics.
And Josefine shows Oskar
the mysterious nativity play.
What do you say then?
Try to see.
- Oskar wants to ask something important.
- Would you like to go steady?
But in her evening prayer, she prays that
Oskar won't be too upset.
Because she has to say
that she doesn't want to be his girlfriend.
on her pillow thoughts stand in line
laid in the soil like flower seeds
shoots and sprouts and winds around
she understands nothing at all
hours feel like days
and weeks a thousand years
came to look back
to a world of yesterday
Jesus and Josefine
homeless heartache
but Jesus makes Josefine
believe in miracles
when she wavers
Jesus and Josefine
faithless time machine
tempter's concubine
she needs miracles
when she wavers
- Oh, it's December fourth.
- Why "oh"?
So there are still twenty days left
until Christmas.
Now you've got some pine needles in your hair.
Actually, I really
liked your raisin buns.
Then you have to taste these.
Come here. Ow…
(groans)
These are the same,
just with star anise.
I call them friendship buns.
I always got them from my best friend.
Look here, Josefine.
There's a letter from the Church Ministry.
When I write to them,
it always takes a month.
That's also because this is important.
Okay, listen.
"Dear Josefine. We have decided
that it's a really good idea, -
- and therefore we're moving Christmas Eve."
- That's not true, is it?
- May I see that?
That's probably not exactly what it says.
"Dear Josefine. We have
assessed the case and have decided, -
— that we cannot comply with
your request to move Christmas Eve.
We apologize and wish you
a happy birthday on 24/12."
Aw.
If you're grumpy,
just stick some fir in your hair.
(phone rings)
Have you thought about it,
I asked you about yesterday?
Not right now.
Can't we talk about it later?
No, hello, Mary and Joseph.
You look fantastic.
- I think that's how they looked.
- Most of it is pretty old.
- Are you sure we can borrow all that?
- Yes, Thorsen has loads of it.
- What is this?
- King Herod is supposed to wear that.
- You can forget that.
- Come on, Emilie.
- I'm not going to look like a clown.
- You won't, Emilie.
I've once seen Herod depicted.
He wore a garment like that.
You take it.
Then I just need the wings,
and I'm an angel.
You must say thank you to your friend.
This is way too much.
Are you ready for the last scene?
Then we just need to get the box out of the way.
That's where Joseph and Mary
have traveled to the land of Egypt -
- with the little Jesus child
and live a life as refugees.
And one day Joseph gets a visit from an angel.
Here you go.
Get up, Joseph of Abraham's lineage.
Take the child and its mother with you
back to the land of Israel.
For the one who wanted to kill the child,
is himself dead.
Maria, King Herod is dead.
- Is that true?
- We're going home. Home to Nazareth.
- What about this one?
- Her name is Josefine.
It's because you were
born in December, -
- and all the good ones are too.
Hi, Josefine.
I've thought about what you asked.
I think I'd mostly like
us just to be friends.
I don't think I'm in love.
I don't feel like
us just being friends.
- Why not?
- Because …
(door slams)
(doorbell rings)
Well, bye, Josefine.
- How did it go with the costumes?
- It went just fine.
Why are you so sad?
- Something with Oskar?
- How can you tell?
I have eyes in my head.
What's wrong?
He doesn't want to be friends anymore.
Well, nothing else?
Nothing else? We're best friends.
We've always been friends.
Josefine, now I'm going to
entrust you with a secret.
Try to look at me.
I have a reasonably good life.
- I think so myself, at any rate.
- And?
And I've lived a long life
without having friends.
Come on, Thorsen. Haven't you missed
having a really good friend?
I would think it was terrible
not to have a good friend.
That's how we're so different.
You know what?
Don't you feel like watching the bitch,
while I run a couple of errands?
- Yes.
- Thank you.
There.
(door creaks)
(wind chimes start)
Thorsen?
What's all this about?
Are you messing with me?
(knocking sounds)
(chickens clucking)
Tell me, is this Afghanistan?
They're playing Kalaha.
Jesus.
Jesus?
Then come and do your work.
- Don't cheat while I'm gone.
- We won't touch the game. Right, Simon?
- I don't trust you, Judas.
- Then it's now, Jesus.
Jesus?
- You have to hold on.
- I'm holding everything I can, Josef.
- Aren't you sweet calling me dad?
- Mom says I mustn't.
- You have to hold on!
- Now he mustn't overexert himself.
So you have to keep an eye on him.
He's just playing Kalaha.
Have you started the game again?
What do you think your dad will say?
- That you have to finish this one.
- I'm not talking about you, Josef.
- I'm talking about Him in Heaven.
- He gave me permission.
You know you're not allowed to lie.
You've gotten lazy lately.
- Go sit and practice your prayers.
- No, now he stays here.
- Who are you?
- Get out of here!
What are you going in there for?
This is a private stable, after all.
What kind of woman was she?
- Let's get back to work.
- She can't just disappear.
Jesus ….
Strange things happen to our family from time to time.
The best thing is not to
think about it.
Think instead about how you
plane a board so it becomes straight.
(doorbell rings)
Hi, Josefine.
Have there been any customers?
- What does that mean?
- There haven't been any.
Someone came for a Christmas star.
- We don't have any of those.
- That's what I said too.
Thanks. Hope it hasn't
been boring.
Not at all.
It's been quiet and peaceful.
Is something wrong?
No no.
I was just thinking about that nativity play.
Yeah, we won't touch that, right?
Now you'll see.
- I have to slip away. Bye.
- Bye bye. You're always welcome.
Look at you, you've started
to take an interest in the Bible.
- Isn't there more about Jesus as a child?
- Yes, there's the Christmas story.
No, not when he was really little,
More when he was my age.
There's actually not much,
but the Gospel of Luke has a story, -
- from when he's 12 and gets lost.
But Joseph and Mary find him
in the temple with the priests.
Is there really nothing more?
It's a long period
that we don't know much about.
- How wild.
- It's actually pretty wild.
He doesn't look like that at all.
All those pictures of Jesus were made
hundreds of years later.
- I think he was red-haired.
- No, he definitely wasn't.
- I don't think he was.
- But you can't know for sure.
What I believe can be
just as good as what you believe, right?
Dear God, or whoever is out there.
If everything that happened today
down at Thorsen's was real -
- and not a dream,
then I'd like to visit Jesus tomorrow.
- Can I come too?
- Lukas, go to sleep now.
I'm already looking forward to it, Amen.