Are you comfortably seated in front of the TV?
Are you ready for a real Christmas story?
"Dear Josefine.
We have assessed the matter …"
Josefine receives a letter from the ministry,
which doesn't want to move Christmas.
She tells Oskar she doesn't want
to get together. Oskar gets angry.
Josefine gets sad.
She visits Thorsen.
He asks her to mind the shop,
while he's out.
Josefine can't keep her fingers from
the mysterious nativity scene.
She gets sucked into the nativity scene —
- and lands in a stable in Nazareth.
Josefine explores Nazareth
2,000 years ago.
She sees Jesus as a 12-year-old
with Simon and Judas.
You lazy rascal.
Can you come and do your work now.
Jesus?
Jesus wants to know who she is.
But Maria chases Josefine away.
Get away!
Jesus finds something on the ground.
Josefine's necklace.
Back home, Josefine sees
a picture of Jesus as a 12-year-old.
He doesn't look like that at all.
In her evening prayer, she asks
to come back and visit Jesus again.
I'm already looking forward to it.
on her pillow thoughts stand in line
laid in the soil like flower seeds
shoot and sprout and twist around
she understands nothing at all
hours feel like days
and weeks a thousand years
came to look back
to a world of yesterday
Jesus and Josefine
homeless heartache
but Jesus gets Josefine
to believe in miracles
when she wavers
Jesus and Josefine
faithless time machine
tempter's concubine
she needs miracles
when she wavers
(panting)
What is that you have there? Get it away.
- It's just a thing I found.
- You got it from that weird one.
Josef says I can keep it.
- Can he keep that one?
- What's wrong with it?
The problem is that it can tempt him
to do something he shouldn't.
Oh well.
As long as you have it cozy and good
and get your food on time, -
- you're indifferent to
whether Jesus fails God.
- Sorry.
- Josef!
You don't break the bread
without blessing it first, do you?
There's nothing to complain about,
if God leaves us one day.
Blessed are you, Lord, our God, -
- King of the universe,
who brings forth bread from the earth.
Thanks,
I just want to say, now the thing is gone.
God came and took it.
- Is that true?
- Of course it's true.
You're cheeky enough,
but you don't lie, right?
Thank you, dear God, for teaching us
to understand what is good for us.
- Eight points.
- Lukas the elf says "eight points".
- What are you doing?
- Blind taste competition in elf beer.
Exciting.
- Six points.
- Six points, you say?
- Minus 13.
- Doesn't affect.
- Ten points.
- Ten? I think we have a winner.
This year's elf beer is:
The elf's elf beer from the Christmas Brewery.
Maybe that should go in your cookbook?
That's a good idea.
Then I can write about that time, -
- me and my friends helped
a lady up with …
We helped a lady carry
a piano up to the fifth floor.
It was summer,
and we were so thirsty.
So when we had carried the piano up,
she offered us something to drink.
She only had elf beer from the previous Christmas,
And that's not exactly what
one feels like in the summer.
But never has
elf beer tasted so good.
- Don't you think about anything else?
- Yes, rice pudding.
- You don't have to drink it.
- You have to in this family.
- What's wrong with you?
- Josefine is grumpy.
I'm not grumpy.
Oskar and I argued yesterday.
- About what?
- Nothing.
- She's grumpy.
- Stop it, Lukas.
Hi, Oskar. Shall we walk together?
- I don't know.
- I experienced something totally wild yesterday.
Then tell it to someone else.
- Don't you want to hear it?
- Nah…
You know what?
Then it doesn't matter either.
- Come, shepherds, let's find the child.
— You're holding those staffs all wrong.
- You have to hold them like a walking stick.
- Where do you know that from?
I've seen it in movies.
(the bell rings)
One moment.
The shepherds can decide for themselves
how to hold their staffs.
As long as the good message
gets through, right, Josefine?
Can you all have a blessed weekend?
See you on Monday and we'll practice more.
Oskar, are you still
upset about yesterday?
Nah.
- Is anyone coming along for the steak?
- We can do that.
(doorbell rings)
Thorsen?
(snoring)
(glockenspiel starts)
(Maria hums)
- Judas, now you owe me a shekel.
- What do you mean?
- You cheated. I've never cheated.
- Judas …
May I play?
- Who are you?
- I'm Josefine.
- This isn't for girls.
- Are you afraid of losing, Jesus?
(laughs)
- How do you know what my name is?
- I just know.
- We'll play a single game.
- Okay.
- What does "okay" mean?
- It's fine. You start.
- Okay.
- Beat her then, Jesus.
You owe her a shekel.
- Thanks.
- Don't thank me. You won it.
Are you actually his disciples?
- Disciples?
- We're his friends.
Simon and Judas. Why did you have
that strange clothing on yesterday?
- That's how we dress where we're from.
- Where are you from?
- A country far to the north.
- Farther away than Rome?
- Near where the world ends?
- No, that's not how the world ends,
- The earth is round.
- What kind of earth?
- Just forget it.
- Aren't you going home?
I think it's you who should go home
and study the ten commandments.
- You should go home now.
- Okay.
I still don't quite get
what "okay" means.
Come.
What are you actually doing here?
Me and my parents
are on our way to Jerusalem.
And we've pitched camp a bit from here.
- My mom thinks you'll tempt me.
- With what?
- She says it belongs to Satan.
- It doesn't.
- What were you doing in the stable yesterday?
- I was hiding.
- We couldn't find you.
- I'm good at hiding.
My mom mustn't see you.
My mom mustn't see this either.
This is Pardo.
He's a gladiator from Rome.
- He's the strongest.
- You like gladiators.
I like Pardo.
He defeats everyone.
- Do you want to be a gladiator yourself?
- I just never want to kill anyone.
- Are you allowed to have guests by your mom?
- It's just Josefine.
She's on her way to Jerusalem
from the country to the north.
Josefine? Josef-ine.
What a pretty name.
- I'm just called Josef.
- Hi, Josef.
If I promise not to tell,
can you do me a favor?
Let's hear it.
You don't have to do anything special.
It's just for me and my friends.
He did it again. My boy.
The water turned to wine.
How cool.
If mom sees it, she'll be furious.
I must not misuse my powers.
I'm the son of God, she says.
Can you fill
this up with apple juice?
- What is apple juice?
- You just have to think "apple juice".
Try tasting it.
It tastes good.
- Jesus?
- I have to go now.
- Hope we see each other again.
- Okay.
Josefine? I had no idea you were here.
I was just checking.
I'll come back tomorrow.
Whoa whoa, you dropped something.
What the hell?
A silver shekel. From Galilee.
You don't see one of those every day.
It's my lucky coin.
I got it from my dad.
I see.
When you have one like that, you really feel
the thrill of history.
Wonder who held
it in their hand?
- Yeah, it's not good to know.
- Hope it brings luck and happiness.
— We shall eat from the same dish.
- No, Lukas.
No, are we having rice pudding?
- There's enough for two days.
- I promised it to Lukas.
Would you mind grabbing
the Nazareth juice from the fridge?
Nazareth juice? What is that?
You drink it with the rice pudding.
You always do before Christmas.
Thanks,
Here.
Do you hate Christmas so much you've forgotten
that Nazareth juice exists?
This is just apple juice.
At Christmas we call it Nazareth juice.
It was something Jesus drank.
- Where do you know that from?
- It's in the Bible. Everyone knows that.
You don't put apple juice
into old leather bags, -
- because then the bags burst,
and the apple juice is wasted.
You put apple juice into new bags,
so both are preserved.
- Matthew, chapter nine, verse …
— 17.
So what happened to gnome beer?
— Gnome beer?
— Yeah.
Gnomes would never think of
drinking anything but Nazareth juice.
There was once,
me and some of my friends -
- had to carry
a piano up to the fifth floor.
It was in the summer.
It was insanely hot.
After we carried the piano up,
we were simply so thirsty.
Then she only had a crate of
old Nazareth juice from the previous Christmas.
That's not exactly what you need
after moving a piano.
Nazareth juice has never tasted so good.
Totally spruce in the hair. Cheers.
Josefine. Cheers.
Dear God.
Or whoever is up there.
It's just been the wildest day.
If you can abolish gnome beer, -
- then maybe
you can make the rice pudding disappear.
I'll ask Jesus about that tomorrow.
- What do you want to talk to Jesus about?
- Just go to sleep now, okay?
Lukas, I think you've eaten
your last portion of rice pudding.