Are you comfortably seated in front of the TV?
Are you ready for a real Christmas story?
Okay.
Down in Thorsen's shop, Josefine
has found a magical nativity game.
With the help of the nativity game, she can
travel to Nazareth 2,000 years ago.
Here she meets Jesus,
when he is her age.
My name is Josefine.
She wants to tell Oskar about it,
but he doesn't want to talk to her.
He's still upset,
because she doesn't want to go steady.
After school, Josefine travels
to Nazareth.
She beats him at Kalaha and teaches him
that "okay" means "alright".
Jesus asks where she's from.
Josefine says she comes from the north.
Farther away than Rome?
Jesus and Josefine become good friends.
Jesus tells that he has
a dream of becoming a gladiator.
- Can you do me a favor?
- Jesus turns a jug of water into wine.
It's just for me and the friends.
Josefine teaches Jesus
to turn a jug of water into apple juice.
When Josefine comes home, she discovers
that people don't drink elf beer anymore.
Instead, people drink apple juice,
which is now called Nazareth juice.
In Josefine's head
a plan begins to take shape.
And in her evening prayer, she asks God
to make the rice pudding disappear.
Lukas, I think you've eaten
your last portion of rice pudding.
on her pillow thoughts stand in line
laid in the soil like flower seeds
shoots and sprouts and winds around
she understands nothing at all
hours feel like days
and weeks a thousand years
came to look back
to a world of yesterday
Jesus and Josefine
homeless heartache
but Jesus gets Josefine
to believe in miracles
when she wavers
Jesus and Josefine
faithless time machine
tempter's concubine
she needs miracles
when she wavers
That doesn't look like you to read the Bible.
I need to see where Jesus drinks juice.
That's a bit wild.
That's not the wildest in the Bible.
- He drank the same as me.
- Yes, and he made the blind see.
I could use some of that
divine help for my back.
There's only Christmas decorations in there.
- There there, dad. Pine needles in your hair.
- Take good care of that back.
— Shall we make a snowscape?
- I have an appointment.
- With whom?
- With no one.
- We don't need to get involved in that.
- I'm not getting involved.
- It's about Oskar, okay?
- Yeah, yeah.
- So we'll see each other for the rice pudding.
- What? You can still have pizza.
No, I think it's cool,
that we eat the same thing.
(doorbell rings)
Hey, Josefine, come here.
Now you're going to see something
really exciting.
Are you ready?
There.
What do you say to that? It just needs
a little life blown into it.
Then that motorcycle will roll for sure.
My dad tried to
fix one like that too.
He gave up.
You might as well learn
that right away.
If you want something badly enough,
then it will succeed.
You have to believe in yourself.
This bike, you know, -
- it reminds me so much of one
I rode when I was young.
When I was a wild angel.
Today I would
have been called a rocker.
- Are you a rocker?
- I was. A real tough guy, you know.
Don't you believe me? Okay.
Then take a look at this. Are you ready?
- What do you say to that?
- Okay.
Now I have such a desire to
get out and get the blood pumping again.
And it's the desire
that drives the work, right?
I mostly want to
wander around and look a bit.
You control that desire yourself. But if you
break something, it costs a krone.
And if you think about Christmas in the meantime,
it costs two kroner.
(sighs)
(chimes start)
- Hi, Jesus.
- Shh, my mother and Joseph are sleeping.
- What are you doing?
- I was just passing by.
- Why aren't you with your family?
- I'd rather visit you.
It's a day of rest. Sabbath.
We don't keep the Sabbath at our house.
Just the weekend.
- Don't you belong to God's people then?
- My mom is a priest, at least.
- Is your mom a priest?
- Is that so strange?
My mom would also be a good priest.
She has me practicing the commandments.
- The commandments?
- God's laws, that Moses got on the mountain.
Isn't it: "You shall not steal"?
"You shall have no other gods."
"Do not misuse God's name."
"Keep the Sabbath holy."
"Honor your father and your mother."
That was five of them.
You get really hungry.
- Me too.
- Just a moment.
Are you almost done?
Don't disturb me now.
I have to write that sermon.
Are you going to wear an elf hat?
In church? No, I don't think so.
(knock on the door)
Hi, Oskar. Will you help me make
a snow landscape?
— Not right now. Is Josefine home?
- I think she had an appointment.
- Isn't she at your place?
- At my place? I just got home.
Have you tried calling her?
(mobile phone rings)
How wild.
- Hello?
- It's Oskar.
- Can't I call a bit later?
- Where are you?
Bye bye, see you.
(busy signal)
- Did you hear a weird sound too?
- Nah.
Well, then it was probably nothing.
Blessed are you, Lord, our God, -
- King of the universe,
who brings forth bread from the earth.
Apple juice?
It's better than what my dad makes.
It reminds me a bit of pizza.
Pizza?
Those round things,
where you put cheese and meat on.
- Isn't cheese made from milk?
- Yes, why?
We must not mix milk and meat.
Can you?
We have a thing
that should be banned. Rice pudding.
- What is rice pudding?
- It's rice boiled in milk.
- And then sprinkled with cinnamon.
- I like cinnamon.
That's the porridge.
It sticks in your throat.
- And it tastes disgusting.
- Okay, I get it.
When you grow up, will you promise me
to ban the rice pudding?
I don't want to
meddle in what people eat.
If you don't promise
to ban the rice pudding, -
- I'm afraid
that I can't visit you again.
Then I swear to ban rice pudding,
if I become a great prophet.
- Jesus?
- Who's that?
Jesus?
jesus!
It's me.
Lord, forgive me. My name is Joshua.
I was once high priest
with old King Herod.
- The one who tried to kill me?
- I tried to prevent it.
I've searched for you everywhere
in Galilee and Judea.
Try to help him.
Give him back his sight.
- I can't do that.
- Yes, you can.
- It's probably forbidden on a Sabbath.
- It doesn't matter what day it is.
- I don't even know how to do it.
- Try.
In God's name.
I give you back your sight.
So, that's what you look like. Son of God.
Thank you, Lord. Thank you.
I will go out into the world and tell, -
- that the Son of God is among us.
I think you should only
thank God, okay?
I don't know the word "okay".
But I'm sure
that it's a divine word.
I've got my sight back. Okay.
The son of God is among us. Okay.
His name is Jesus. He's okay.
What's that noise, Jesus?
Jesus has given me my sight back.
- He's the son of God.
- What are you doing …
Are you out of your mind?
If mom finds out you're doing something like that
on a sabbath, she'll be furious.
Shall we just agree
not to say anything to her?
You know what? It's fine.
Just make a jug like that.
Joseph?
What's this? Are you tempting him
to turn water into wine?
I just felt like having a jug.
I don't want
him using his powers on nonsense.
That's no worse than giving
the blind their sight back on a sabbath.
You shall keep the sabbath holy.
It doesn't matter
what day it is.
Say something to him.
No, I'm about to give up.
Lord, forgive us.
(doorbell rings)
Hey, Oskar.
- Is Josefine here?
- No, I haven't seen her.
Oh, there she is.
- Where were you when I rang?
- Nowhere.
- Are you dating someone else?
- No.
- Are you seeing someone else?
There's no one in there.
(door slams)
- He's still upset, I guess.
- Yeah.
But remember: Friendship isn't
the most important thing in life.
So what's the most important?
It's that the spark plugs work.
(motorcycle roars)
What do you say now?!
(motorcycle stalls)
Oops.
- Hi.
- Hi. I never thought you'd come.
- Hi, Josefine.
- Hi, mom.
- Did you have a good day?
- Yeah, it was okay.
- I was over at Oskar's.
- At Oskar's?
He was just here.
He's called a few times too.
- That's weird, since you've been together.
- Yeah, it sounds strange.
You should also be allowed to
have your little secrets.
- Then there's Christmas pizza.
- Yes! I love Christmas pizza.
Weren't we supposed to have rice pudding?
- Now you behave.
- Ugh, how gross.
Remember, this is a priest's home.
- What's wrong with rice pudding?
- You know very well.
It's not because it's forbidden, -
- but Jesus said
it was bad to mix rice and milk.
It's the porridge.
It sticks in my throat.
Then I swear to ban rice porridge.
It's better than what my dad makes.
It reminds me a bit of pizza.
Those round things,
where you put cheese and meat on.
There you go.
I love Christmas pizza.
Dear God, or whoever
is up there.
Thanks for another wild day.
That was sweet of Jesus,
he wanted to abolish rice porridge.
- Who's sweet?
- No one. Turn around and sleep.
So I hope I can come by
and visit Jesus again tomorrow.
If only he'd move his birthday,
so I can keep mine to myself.
Amen.