Are you comfortably seated in front of the TV?
Are you ready for a real Christmas story?
Okay. Down in Thorsen's shop
Josefine has found a magical nativity game.
With the help of the nativity game, she can
travel to Nazareth 2,000 years ago.
Here she meets Jesus,
when he is her age.
It's Sabbath, the day of rest.
It sticks in the throat
and tastes disgusting. Yuck.
Josefine wants him to
ban rice pudding.
While they talk,
Josefine's mobile rings.
- Hello?
- It's Oskar.
- Where are you?
- I'll call later.
- A blind beggar approaches Jesus.
— Jesus.
It's Joshua,
King Herod's old high priest.
- I can't do that.
- Yes, you can.
In God's name,
I restore your sight.
Joshua wants to go out and tell
that the Son of God is among them.
His name is Jesus. He's okay.
When Josefine returns,
she meets Oskar.
- He wants to know if she has another.
— No.
At home, Josefine discovers that according to
the Bible, it's wrong to eat rice pudding.
- Aren't we having rice pudding?
- Now you mind yourself.
Remember, this is a priest's home.
Josefine prays that Jesus moves
his birthday so she can have hers in peace.
on her pillow thoughts stand in line
laid in the soil like flower seeds
shoots and sprouts and winds around
she understands nothing at all
hours feel like days
and weeks a thousand years
came to look back
to a world of yesterday
Jesus and Josefine
homeless heartache
but Jesus gets Josefine
to believe in miracles
when she wavers
Jesus and Josefine
faithless time machine
tempter's concubine
she needs miracles
and love
when she wavers
(organ music)
- Why doesn't anyone have elf hats on?
- Because only stupid kids believe in elves.
Shh. Mom is very nervous.
There's nothing to be
nervous about, there's no one here.
Let us all pray,
- Elf hats, elf hats …
- Shh.
When we read today's gospel
about the adult Jesus, -
- who tells about God's kingdom, -
- we meet a man
who knows what he wants.
If we leaf back in the Bible,
we meet a somewhat different Jesus.
The 12-year-old Jesus knew,
that he was extraordinary.
His mother had told him that.
But he didn't quite believe it.
He hid his light under a bushel.
Then a girl came
from a country to the North.
He didn't know her.
He didn't know who she was.
- Where are you from?
- A country far to the North.
Farther away than Rome?
But Jesus trusted her, -
- and the girl from the North
helped him to believe, -
- so he restored sight to a blind man,
and on a Sabbath.
- Did Jesus wear an elf hat?
- Shh.
So even though Jesus was God's son,
he was also a human.
And he wasn't too proud
to accept help -
- from a perfectly ordinary girl
from the North.
Hi.
If I don't get better,
I can't fill the church on Christmas Eve.
- Believe in yourself.
- No, not flour on the priest's robe.
That girl from the North,
who was she really?
- Is that my daughter there?
- Yes yes, I definitely think so.
Who doesn't know the girl from the North.
You learned about her in kindergarten.
I can't remember all
the Bible stories. You can't at all.
Oh well, but anyway, just the girl from the North.
Everyone remembers her, don't they?
I was crazy about her as a kid.
You know the girl from the North, right?
- What was her name?
- I don't really know.
- Does the Bible say anything about it?
- She was just someone who helped Jesus.
- Maybe she was an angel.
- She was an ordinary girl.
I believe she was an angel.
How wild.
Yeah, the Bible is
actually pretty wild.
We also need to come up with a name for
the buns. What should we call them?
- Girl from the North buns?
- Okay.
(doorbell)
- Thorsen?
- Hi there. How nice to see you.
- Are you open on Sundays?
- No, I work when I feel like it.
Not that I feel like it now,
but this box arrived this morning.
- They're nice.
- Do you collect glitter cards?
Couldn't you help me
sort these?
We could do it by putting
all animals in one folder, -
- and people in another, and postcards
could go in a third folder, and …
And everything that just smells
of Christmas … that goes out.
- Is there any with the girl from the North on?
- The girl from the North?
Yeah. Yeah.
What do you say to this one?
She's beautiful.
- She's an angel.
- Yeah, wasn't she?
That's what they say anyway.
She helped Jesus.
If only she had helped him
forbid people from celebrating Christmas.
Now I'll help myself
by fixing my motorcycle. See you.
(chimes)
- The balls aren't rolling right for you.
- Relax, I'll beat you.
Hi, Jesus.
- Josefine, good to see you.
- I've got the girl from Nord-boller with me.
They look good.
- What about your game, Jesus?
- Can't it wait until later?
If it's your turn, you can win.
- It's me and Jesus playing.
- Come on, Simon.
- Where are you two going?
- We have an appointment.
- Your dad is good at baking.
- I can ask him to make some more.
But then you have to do me a favor.
- You have to abolish Christmas Eve.
- What is Christmas Eve?
An evening we observe in my country,
where we celebrate your birthday.
- How do you know?
- It's the same day as mine.
- When is it?
- In 17 days.
Can't you give a speech
where you say you don't want to be celebrated?
- I'm tired of sharing with others.
- We share your dad's buns equally.
Yes, that's quite right, of course.
If you give that speech,
then I will …
- Teach you to walk on water.
- Nobody can do that.
You can. Come.
- I can't.
- You just have to believe you can.
- How?
- Put one foot in front of the other and walk.
- Then walk.
- Can you walk on water?
- No.
- Why not?
- Because I don't believe I can.
- Then I don't believe I can either.
My sandal! What are you doing?
Go get it.
- Do you believe in me now?
- I believe in you.
(thunder)
Don't worry, I believe in you most of all, God.
- Have you seen Jesus?
- Nah.
- He said he was going to help you.
- I haven't noticed much of that.
Simon, Judas, come here,
- Have you seen Jesus?
- No.
You're lying.
I can see it on you, Simon.
Maria, that doesn't help at all.
It takes completely different measures.
Boys, listen up, you'll get a coin
if you tell me where Jesus is.
- He…
- We haven't seen him.
That's fine. Just run along.
Worth a try.
- Uh, sorry.
- Yes? What is it, Judas?
I just want to say Jesus is walking
around on the water with that girl.
- What?
- On the water?
- I'll get you a coin.
- What are you telling me?
- Nothing.
- You stay here.
- So where have you been?
- Josefine has heard me on the Ten Commandments.
Aha, so can you tell me
the eighth commandment?
Jesus?
You shall not lie. Judas saw you walking around down by the river.
I didn't tattle.
I didn't.
- Here, you honestly earned this.
- Tattletale.
I don't want you using
your divine powers on nonsense.
- I don't want that.
- Remember about the birthday, okay?
And I don't want to see you here again.
Can you get lost.
Get lost, I said.
Pst. In with you.
Scram then. When Maria is in that mood,
she's not to be trifled with.
- How's it going with the glitter pictures?
- Fine. I'm just nowhere near done.
I'll be done with the motorcycle before
you're done with the glitter pictures.
In any case, I'll be
done before your birthday on the 24th.
Isn't it Christmas
on my birthday anymore?
Not if you really believe it.
Then you get what you want.
- Has Christmas been abolished?
- Ho, ho, ho.
You know perfectly well
that the word Christmas is forbidden here.
You're probably not the right one to ask.
See you.
Hi.
Can you tell me
what date Christmas Eve is?
- Isn't it the 27th of December?
— Is it?
You're too easy. It's the 24th,
as it always is.
Why's that?
Oh, no reason.
- Okay, what's his name?
- Who?
Yeah, the one you see all the time.
- Who says I'm seeing anyone?
- I do. What's his name?
If you really want to know,
his name is Jesus.
Jesus. Now you need to mind your own business.
Alright, I'm heading home.
(door slams)
This is a German Christmas cake.
When people have read my cookbook,
anyone can just make this cake.
I think it's burnt on the bottom.
No, it looks good, Jesper.
Believe in yourself. Pine needle in your hair.
Hello, Josefine.
We haven't seen much of you today.
- A piece of burnt Christmas cake?
- I'm not hungry.
- Is something wrong?
- I've been cheated.
What happened to the girl from the North?
Some say
that Maria chased her away, -
— because she taught Jesus
to walk on water.
Others believe
she was sold to the Romans -
- and ended her days
as a slave in Rome.
- A slave?
- It's just a good story.
- I actually think that one's true enough.
- There are so many colorful stories,
Dear God, or whoever you are.
Jesus, he actually promised me
to move his birthday.
Let me come down, so I can
sort this all out once and for all.
Yeah, and I'd rather not end up
as a slave in Rome.
- Want some rum?
- Relax, Lukas.
I don't think the world has heard
the last of the girl from the North.