Are you comfortably seated in front of the TV?
Are you ready for a real Christmas story?
- Okay.
- When we read today's gospel …
It's Sunday,
and Louise is going to preach in church.
- Then a girl came from a country in the North.
- Josefine pricks up her ears.
Josefine questions Jesper
about the girl from the North.
- Jesper says that everyone knows her.
- You know the girl from the North, right?
- Yes, definitely.
- What was her name?
- Is it in the Bible?
- She was just one who helped Jesus.
And Josefine discovers that she
has been written into the Bible.
What should I call those buns?
Girl from the North-buns?
Josefine takes them with her
when she visits Jesus.
If Jesus wants to abolish Christmas Eve,
Josefine will teach him to walk on water.
- I can't do that.
- You just have to believe that you can.
Simon and Judas see it,
and Judas tells on him to Joseph and Mary.
- What?
- On the water?
Maria scolds Jesus. He must not
use his divine power for nonsense.
I never want to see you here again.
Get out of here.
- What date is Christmas Eve?
- The 24th, as usual.
When Josefine comes home, she discovers
that Jesus hasn't moved Christmas.
What's his name?
- His name is Jesus.
- Oskar doesn't believe that.
on her pillow thoughts stand in line
laid in the earth like flower seeds
shoots and sprouts and winds around
she understands nothing at all
hours feel like days
and weeks a thousand years
came to look back
to a world of yesterday
Jesus and Josefine
homeless heartache
but Jesus gets Josefine
to believe in miracles
when she wavers
Jesus and Josefine
faithless time machine
the tempter's concubine
she needs miracles
and love
when she wavers
(cock crow)
Josefine. Josefine.
You are so beautiful.
Your eyes behind the veil are like doves.
Your hair is like a flock of goats,
that wave down the mountain.
Joseph. Come and listen for a moment.
Your lips are like scarlet thread.
- Your mouth is lovely.
- Jesus has fallen in love.
Your temple is like
a bursting pomegranate.
He heard that in the synagogue.
Yes, it's Solomon's Song of Songs.
The most beautiful place in the holy book.
So he's not in love after all.
He's just doing homework.
Don't you understand anything at all?
That crazy girl from the North
has turned his head.
Jesus is 12 years old.
How old were you
when you started chasing girls?
- Yeah, I can't remember that. Come on.
- But never …
- He's way too young for that.
- Come on, stop it.
Josefine, you are so beautiful.
Your lips are like scarlet thread.
Your mouth is lovely.
- So there are 16 days left until Christmas.
- I can't stand it any longer.
I actually like
looking forward to something.
- It tickles so nicely in the stomach.
- Are you in love?
No, I just like Christmas.
Of course I'm in love with you.
Pst, Mom.
- Josefine is in love.
- Is that true?
In the evening she whispers about one
who is sweet.
- What are you talking about?
- Uh, nothing. Nothing important.
Did you sleep well?
No, I dreamed that someone had promised me to
move Christmas, but he didn't do it.
That sounds like a good old-fashioned
Josefine dream, I think.
- Don't you want some heart bread?
- Isn't that just regular French bread?
I want to call it something fun
for the baking book.
Then I can tell about the young man
who repairs the young woman's bike.
The young woman invites him home,
because she has baked bread.
And when she hands the bread to him,
she touches something in his heart.
And he in hers. That's the story of
how dad and mom met.
That one goes in the book too.
And you get some cornflakes.
- Will you fetch Lukas?
- Why?
I have to hold a meeting,
and dad has to go to the chiropractor.
- I have an important appointment.
- You'll have to reschedule it.
- Yeah, because we're going to visit Santa Claus.
- What are we going to do?
- I'm going to be Santa's helper.
- He can win a Santa suit.
- I don't want to.
- You could use a little time on that.
So, did you have a good weekend?
My dad went to the Christmas lunch,
so he's been sick.
My mom was too.
- Oskar, did you have a good weekend?
- It was okay.
But Josefine has been with
Jesus the whole weekend.
Oh yeah.
You said yourself
that your boyfriend is called Jesus.
- How embarrassing.
- I don't have a boyfriend.
She is allowed to
keep that to herself.
- Are you boyfriend with the real Jesus?
- You can't be.
There are actually some Christians
who devote their lives to Jesus.
- That's like having a boyfriend.
- Have you devoted your life to Jesus?
- I taught him to walk on water.
- Sure.
Now you stop arguing.
We also need to move on.
Oskar and Josefine. We're doing
the flight from Bethlehem again.
Can you hold hands? Then we need
the Roman soldiers ready here.
Where are the others? There they are.
- Do we have to hold hands?
- It's part of the play.
Just do it now, Oskar.
(whistle)
Hi, Oskar.
How about babysitting Lukas?
- Are you going over to your girlfriend?
- I don't have a girlfriend.
- Yes, you do.
- No, I don't.
- I have an appointment.
- I'm going over to Emilie in an hour.
- Emilie?
- Yeah. She's actually okay.
- I'm in a hurry. See you, Lukas.
- No! Hey, you can't do that!
I'm going to Santa
and be Santa's helper.
- Won't you help change the hay?
- No, I won't.
- Argh.
- No.
Try looking at the goats. Try looking.
(doorbell)
- Hi. I'm a bit busy today.
- I have to help with the glitter pictures.
Yes, but not if it's a sour duty,
only if it's a pleasure for you.
Is something wrong?
It's a friend who promised me to do
something, which he then didn't do.
I've told you,
that friends, you can't rely on them.
Is it Oskar?
If it's something that you think
you really have a right to, -
- then you should demand your right.
Sure.
(chimes)
- Hi.
I don't want to prevent people from
celebrating my birthday.
- I want to be celebrated the same day as you.
— Do you mean that?
Then I'm afraid we two don't
have more to talk about. Goodbye.
- No no. Where are you going?
- Home.
- You mustn't.
— Why?
I've missed you.
Well
a
- Are you almost done?
- Almost.
You dare come back after yesterday?
Tell me once, Josefine.
That land far to the north,
where is it actually?
It lies pretty far to the north.
Aha.
And your father,
how many camels does he have?
He has a bicycle.
A bicycle? How many camels
can you get for one like that?
What is she doing here? I don't want to see
her here in Nazareth. She must go. Now.
- You don't decide who I see.
— Yeah.
Jesus.
Come.
Your mother apparently doesn't like me.
I do.
There's something I really want to say.
Your eyes behind the veil are like doves.
Your hair is like a flock of goats,
flowing down the mountain.
- Flock of goats?
- Your lips are like a scarlet thread.
Your mouth is lovely.
No one has ever said
anything like that to me before.
Is it okay that I said it then?
It's okay.
- What is it?
— A heart.
(mobile phone rings)
- That sound is coming from you.
- Wait a minute.
- Oskar, I don't have time now.
- Lukas is gone.
I was getting something,
and when I got back, he was gone.
- Didn't he say what he was doing?
- He was going to visit Santa Claus.
I know where he is.
- What is that thing?
- It's nothing.
- Who are you talking to?
- Someone I know.
- Is it maybe Jesus?
- Oskar, I'm coming right away.
- So I have to go.
- Did the thing say you had to?
Aren't you coming back then?
Yeah yeah.
- Ho ho ho!
- Yeah, ho ho ho.
It's great
that you became Santa's helper.
But it's stupid to run off
without saying anything.
- Do you want a pepper nut, Josefine?
- No thanks.
- Where does that Jesus live?
- Far from here.
- Do you know Jesus?
— Yes.
- That can't be done.
- I've found a time machine.
- Can I come along?
- It's something she's making up.
- Yeah, that's what we'll say.
Oops, Oskar got mad.
Ho ho ho.
Won't it be good?
You eat heart bread on December 8th.
Yeah, it'll probably be fine enough.
- What is Lukas actually saying?
- What does Lukas say?
- That you've got a girlfriend.
- I don't.
- It's Jesus.
- Just shut up, Lukas.
- Jesus?
- Josefine actually has a time machine.
So you travel back and forth in time
from Denmark to Bethlehem?
- Nazareth.
- Nazareth, of course. That's obvious.
He's okay, isn't he.
So that's why you always look in the Bible.
Before, you couldn't stand Jesus.
- I actually can now.
- Hi. What are you talking about?
- Wow!
- Santa, you look so nice.
Josefine has got a time machine,
that she travels back in time with.
- Oh, darn.
- And she's become Jesus's girlfriend.
— We're not boyfriend and girlfriend.
- They're good friends.
- Don't pay attention to him.
- I just found out myself.
- Can I come along?
- No.
Santa's helper should come along,
when you travel back in time.
We can all just come along,
right?
- No, sorry, Josefine.
- It's okay.
I'm traveling back in time.
Hi, Jesus. Spruce in the hair.
I'll put spruce in your hair,
I will.
Dear God,
or whoever is out there.
It doesn't matter if I can't
have my birthday to myself.
Something much bigger has happened.
Jesus, he has fallen in love with me.
And I am also in love with him.
- I am also in love with Jesus.
- Lukas, be quiet.
I pray to be allowed to be
alone with him again tomorrow. Amen.