Are you comfortably seated in front of the TV?
Are you ready for a real Christmas story?
- Okay.
- Your eyes behind the veil are …
In Nazareth, Maria is worried.
Is her son in love with Josefine?
You are so beautiful.
Your mouth is lovely.
Jesus has fallen in love. The girl
from the North has turned his head.
Louise asks
if Josefine will look after Lukas.
- I have an appointment.
- Yeah, right.
Josefine promises
and gets Oskar to look after him.
- Hi, Oskar. See you, Lukas.
- No! Hey, you can't do that!
While she herself visits Jesus.
Jesus says
that he is in love with her.
- At that moment Oskar calls.
- I don't have time now.
Lukas has disappeared.
Josefine has to go back.
- Aren't you coming back then?
- Yes, yes.
When they have found Lukas, Oskar wants
to hear more about her new friend, Jesus.
Where does that Jesus live?
Josefine explains she has discovered a
time machine. Oskar doesn't believe her.
- Yeah, let's say that.
In her evening prayer, Josefine tells
that she has fallen in love with Jesus.
on her pillow thoughts stand in line
laid in the soil like flower seeds
shoots and sprouts and winds around
she understands nothing at all
hours feel like days
and weeks a thousand years
came to look back
to a world of yesterday
Jesus and Josefine
homeless heartache
but Jesus gets Josefine
to believe in miracles
when she wavers
Jesus and Josefine
faithless time machine
the tempter's concubine
she needs miracles
and love
when she wavers
Good morning.
You're up early, aren't you?
- What are you looking for?
- Something more about that girl from the North.
- You like her, huh?
- Did she and Jesus become sweethearts?
Now Jesus didn't have sweethearts,
but a rather unknown text suggests it.
- What kind of text is that?
- It's not one that's in the Bible.
It's an ancient folk tale
most consider nonsense.
- I think they became sweethearts.
- No.
- Why not?
- Because …
Jesus just didn't have any sweethearts,
I think.
- Are you talking about Jesus again?
- Yes, that's nice.
Not at this time of the morning, huh?
- Wanna fight?
- Yes.
Here you go, Herod.
All male children under two years
in Bethlehem shall be captured and murdered, -
- so I can put an end to
this king of the Jews.
Yes, that's fine, Emilie, but I want
to feel a bit more malice.
Imagine, you're king in a country,
you have soldiers under you, -
- you're under the Romans' protection, -
- and there's nothing
that can threaten you.
And yet you choose
to kill the little children.
Come on, try again.
A bit more malice in the voice.
Ready? Go ahead, Herod.
All male children in Bethlehem
shall be murdered. Ha ha.
He's at least not
a cuddly baby.
(doorbell)
(Thorsen panting and groaning)
Hi, Josefine.
What are you saying then, huh?
Is it so the motorcycle
can go faster?
No. It's so
it looks cooler.
What do you girls know about beauty? You think
it's sitting on a beachfront -
- and interlacing fingers with the one
you're in love with.
- I can see you're in love.
- How so?
That's girls your age.
But do you know what?
Falling in love, it's nothing but
a short circuit in the brain.
- What are you saying then?
- Yeah, that's fine, Thorsen.
Say hi to the pin-ups.
There.
(chimes)
Jesus.
- Hi, Josefine.
- Hey, Jesus.
- We're leaving right away.
- Where are we going?
- Pardos has come to Nazareth.
- Who's Pardos?
- That gladiator I told you about.
- Wait a minute.
- Can't we just talk?
- He might be gone by then. Come on.
(rattling chains)
Ah.
(whip crack and cry of pain)
Now watch this.
- Is Pardos coming down there?
- His stuff is still there.
I saw those Romans
crucify a man.
No, Jesus. Jesus, come. Jesus.
I can easily beat you. Take that.
Why did they crucify that man?
He rebelled.
Is anyone there?
So what? Are there more
who want to fight before I move on?
No thanks, Pardos.
- What? Are you sure?
- Yes.
Sissies.
There's no point in putting on
a show when no one dares to step up.
- I dare.
- Who are you?
I'm Jesus, and this is Josefine,
Hey, Jesus and Josefine.
I don't fight children, after all.
I'm not a child.
Jesus.
Come on. Come on. Don't you dare?
Then come on. Come on.
Come on.
Jesus.
Watch out, or you'll end up in chains.
- You have talent, boy.
- You think so?
Yes. The world is waiting for you. You'll be
the greatest. Everyone will know your name.
Whoa
Jesus, watch out.
Watch where you stand. Otherwise
your career will be short, Jesus.
You're actually pretty good.
(mobile phone rings)
(presses a button)
Hello?
Hello, Josefine?
Hello? What's happening?
- Is that the angel?
- The angel?
- Sorry, who am I speaking to?
- This is Josef.
- Josef of Nazareth.
- If you're Josef, then I'm …
- God.
- God?
Hey to you, Josef.
Sorry if I haven't behaved
properly, but I'm just a carpenter.
- You're good enough, Josef.
- Is that true? Am I good enough?
- Well, thank you very much.
- Who are you talking to?
Yes, it's the Lord.
He says I'm good enough.
Hello?
Hello? What's happening?
Get that away, Josef.
Josef, come. Josef.
(the sheep bleats, and the phone beeps)
- How does one become a gladiator?
- It's slaves who are forced.
- Listen. No one wants to become a gladiator.
- I do.
There's an opportunity for a talent.
In Caesarea there's a gladiator school.
- What is that? Can you come out then!
- Those are my friends.
Sorry, Pardos. But I don't want to see children from the village here.
- But we're talking.
- Come on.
- Can't I just come with you?
- Goodbye.
Nothing good has ever come
from Nazareth.
- I'm just saying, Pardos is okay.
- But you don't need to become a gladiator.
What is this?
You're really sent by Satan.
- It's Satan's work.
- It's my mobile.
I've said it before: Stay away
from my son. Satan's emissary.
- She prevented me from becoming a gladiator.
- Why would you become a gladiator?
- Because you're so tough.
- I'm watching out.
- Then he gets some dumb ideas.
- Gladiator is not a dumb idea.
That's not entirely wrong.
You're a bit tough.
Yeah, but am I that tough?
- Let's leave them alone for a bit.
- We can't leave them alone.
Come on, Maria.
Weren't you baking something?
- I have to go home too.
- I'll get your phone for you tomorrow.
(Maria clears her throat)
See you,
Hey, Josefine.
I called, and then I got hold of a guy,
who was named Josef.
He sounded like someone,
who had never spoken on a mobile.
- That was probably my dad.
- That wasn't his voice.
My dad is pretty good at disguising
his voice. Goodbye, Oskar.
(war cry)
- No, there's nothing about that.
- About what?
- About Jesus wanting to be a gladiator.
- No, there's probably nothing about that.
- Stop that.
- It's my calendar gift.
Come here.
You're sitting with that Bible all the time.
Didn't you want Christmas removed?
Yes. Jesus doesn't know anyway,
when he was born.
Jesus doesn't know.
Didn't know, you mean, right?
- He might never have existed.
- Yes, Jesper. He has.
- It could be a Robin Hood story.
- Didn't Robin Hood exist?
Josefine is allowed to
be interested in Jesus.
(phone rings)
There are limits, right?
It's Jesper.
Just a moment.
Josefine, it's Jesus.
- This is Josefine.
- I wanted to say, I have your phone.
- Then I'll come over tomorrow.
- Jesus, what are you doing?
- How do you turn it off?
- Press the red button.
It's not his fault,
his name is Jesus.
Dear God,
or whoever is out there.
Dad and mom think,
Jesus is an ordinary boy.
That's fine. Thanks for the help.
And now it's about time that Jesus
becomes boyfriend with the girl from the North.
- Are you boyfriend with the girl from the North?
- Go to sleep now, Lukas.
Jesus could well take
to become boyfriend with the girl from the North.