Are you comfortably seated in front of the TV?
Are you ready for a real Christmas story?
Okay. Josefine visits Jesus.
Hi, Josefine.
We're heading off right away.
She thinks they're going to look deeply
into each other's eyes, but Jesus has other plans.
The gladiator Pardos has come to
Nazareth and is going to perform for the Romans.
But none of the Roman soldiers
dare challenge Pardos.
- Jesus dares.
- I dare, sure.
I don't fight against children.
Come on then. Come on.
- He fights bravely, but…
- Jesus, watch out.
Watch where you're standing.
Meanwhile, Joseph finds Josefine's phone
and gets a call from Oskar.
- Is that the angel?
- The angel?
Oskar asks who he was talking to,
I called, and then I got hold of someone
named Joseph.
He had never talked on a mobile.
And the family is a bit surprised
that a guy named Jesus…
- Josefine, it's Jesus.
- … Says he has her phone.
It's not his fault,
he's named Jesus.
on her pillow thoughts stand in line
laid in the ground like flower seeds
shoots and sprouts and winds around
she understands nothing at all
hours feel like days
and weeks a thousand years
came to look back
to a world of yesterday
Jesus and Josefine
homeless heartache
but Jesus gets Josefine
to believe in miracles
when she wavers
Jesus and Josefine
faithless time machine
the tempter's concubine
she needs miracles
and love
when she wavers
(egg timer rings, and baking tray is taken out)
- Would you like more coffee?
— Yes please.
- Good morning.
- Look, I've baked Jesus-buns.
- Now stop teasing her.
I'm not teasing. I'm glad
Josefine has become friends with Jesus.
Mm.
I just don't understand
where you know him from.
Up at school.
Is his name Jesus,
or is it just something you call him?
Well, I don't think he's been baptized that.
Many are named Jesus
in Spain and South America.
His parents come
from the south anyway.
- Where does he live?
- A road called Nazareth Road.
Nazareth Road? It's very good.
What do his parents do?
- His father works with wood.
- Oh, he's in the carpentry business?
- His mother bakes bread and washes clothes.
- Does she bake bread?
You're always welcome
to take your Jesus home.
That's not my Jesus.
I'd like to meet Jesus.
Then he can teach me to walk on water.
Now it's probably not exactly the Jesus
Josefine knows. Right, Josefine?
Can't I take some of those buns
with me to Jesus?
Those are Jesus buns,
of course you can. Pine needles in your hair.
- Oh, Maria. King Herod is dead.
- Is that true, Joseph?
- Oh, we're going home. Home to Nazareth.
- Why do you say "oh" all the time?
- It's because it sounds good.
- "Oh, Maria", that sounds beautiful.
- He doesn't talk like that.
- How then?
- Like that fool who took your phone?
— Yes.
- I'd like to say hi to him.
- You don't dare.
- Are you going to argue for long?
- You're dead, so shut up.
Come on, Josefine, speak properly now.
Now we have to redo the scene. From where
Joseph gets a visit from an angel.
- Why don't I dare?
- You're a sissy.
Oh, Joseph. Get up.
Take the child and its mother
back to the land of Israel.
For the one who wanted to kill the child
is himself dead.
Oh, Maria. King Herod is dead.
Is that true, oh, Joseph?
We're going home.
Home to oh, Nazareth.
(doorbell)
- Hi. You've got new glasses.
- You could say that.
Hey, watch your eyes.
There's a hole in the gas tank,
so I need to cut a new piece for it.
There.
- Hey, can you use one like this?
- I've never tried.
It's about controlling the fire.
Making the fire your servant.
Fire breaks all chains.
It's very good to know.
You light it up here. Like that.
And extinguish it here.
Fire is actually stronger than iron.
I'll just finish
the shiny pictures, okay?
Yeah yeah, you can fix whatever you want.
There.
(doorbell)
Is anyone here? Hm.
(ding-dong)
Josefine,
(chimes)
The boy who's okay.
Yes. What is it? What is it?
You? Are you okay?
Give us back our sight.
- I can't do that.
- Aren't you the boy who's okay?
- No.
- So where is the boy who is okay?
- Come on, give them their sight back, Jesus.
- Jesus?
You are the Jesus who is okay.
Yes. So you could go ahead and
give us our sight back.
- Okay.
- Yes, yes.
Yes, yes.
Oh, oh.
Dear God the Father, give these two
blind beggars their sight back.
(astonished exclamations)
- Thank you, Jesus.
- See to it you don't tell anyone.
No, we won't tell anyone.
He gave us our sight back.
He is greater than the king.
Yes, he is greater
than the emperor of Rome!
Yes, he is greater. That's Jesus.
If the Romans hear this,
9 Fi
then they'll come after me.
Josephine,
(chimes)
- I'd like a cell phone.
- Oh, so you would.
Then I could talk to you
when you're not here.
- Hey.
- Oskar, what are you doing here?
- Are we in a nativity play?
- Have you followed me?
- Why didn't you say so?
- I tried.
So that's "Jesus"?
Yes, Oskar, that's Jesus.
The real Jesus.
Are you Jesus?
- Who's he?
- That's Oskar, my little brother.
- I'm taller than you.
- Good for you. We're going now.
Stop! Are you the one they call okay?
- Is this an Asterix movie?
- Answer. Are you the one who is okay?
I think myself,
I'm reasonably okay.
He calls himself greater than the emperor.
- It's a misunderstanding.
- You two stay away. Take him away.
So you're the little miracle worker
who's been stirring things up in Nazareth lately, huh?
- The boy they call okay.
- Are you perhaps Caesar?
- Pontius Aurelius, if I may.
- Yeah, okay, forget it.
Yeah, I thought as much.
You are him, the one who is okay.
You're well aware that the Roman Empire
doesn't like people at all who -
- mock their emperor, right?
- The Roman Empire will collapse in 400 years.
- The Roman Empire will never collapse!
Tell me, are you trying to
make false prophecies, huh?
The punishment for that is even harsher
than the punishment for miracle-working.
What shall we do with the miracle worker?
Take him to Caesarea tomorrow,
and sentence him to the galleys!
I'm not going on any galley.
Put him in chains.
Remove that one. Like that.
You must not sleep.
We have to free him.
- But the chain is made of iron.
- We'll find something stronger.
The only thing stronger
than iron is gold.
- Fire. Fire is stronger than iron.
— Fire?
I'll be there in a bit.
Thorsen.
- Did you finish with the glitter pictures?
- Can't I borrow the burner?
- Do you have something you need cut?
- I'd like to learn to use it.
- Yes, but not today, I'm busy.
- When then? Later tonight?
Uh, no. No, that won't work.
I have to work all night.
And besides, cutting torches
aren't for kids.
Oh no.
(cell phone rings)
- Josefine?
- Are you okay?
No, I'm not okay at all.
You have to get me out of here.
— Not until tomorrow.
- Then I'll be sentenced to the galleys.
- We'll get you out.
- What about my parents?
- Call and say you're sleeping at my place.
- How is there cell signal?
It must be the crib,
that works as a transmitter.
Just hope we don't get a huge bill.
Oskar, see you.
(the guards chat)
Here you go.
What is that?
(Jesper clears his throat)
- Welsh Christmas pudding.
- Why is it green?
It's crushed peppermint leaves.
Chocolate sauce on top. Here you go.
What did it mean
to be sentenced to the galleys?
- Are you interested in the Roman Empire?
- Maybe a little.
It was a quite normal punishment, -
- given to pickpockets, prisoners of war, and
others who got in trouble back then.
- What's a galley?
- Some huge, flat rowboats.
They sailed around the Mediterranean filled
with slaves who had to row in rhythm.
And there was one beating a drum.
And if they didn't row, they got whipped.
In return, I think they got
some proper biceps from rowing.
Maybe
I should make a galley cake.
There's not much grey hair involved
in making a galley cake.
- What are you doing?
- I'm going to bed.
- It's only half past six.
- But I'm tired.
Goodnight.
Dear God. Just let me save
Oskar from the galley tomorrow.
- Do you have galleys?
- Hush, Lukas.
- I want galleys too.
- I don't have any galleys, so go to sleep.
It just has to work.
Otherwise I don't know
what to do. Amen.