Are you sitting comfortably in front of the TV?
Are you ready for a real Christmas story?
Okay. Jesper and Louise ask about
that Jesus that Josefine knows.
- Is his real name Jesus?
- I don't think he's been baptized that.
- Where does he live?
- On a road called Nazareth Road.
Oskar follows Josefine
to Thorsen's shop.
He discovers
the secret of the nativity play.
- Suddenly Oskar shows up in Nazareth.
- Oskar, what are you doing here?
Is that "Jesus" then?
, oa
- Come, let's go now.
- Stop!
- The soldiers capture Oskar.
- Are you the one they call okay?
- I think I'm pretty okay myself.
- He calls himself greater than the emperor.
- It's a misunderstanding.
- You stay away.
He is put in chains
and sentenced to the galleys.
We have to free him.
Josefine wants to free him
with Thorsen's log splitter.
But Thorsen needs it
all night.
And besides, log splitters
aren't for children.
- Oskar, are you okay?
- No, I'm not okay at all.
Josefine promises Oskar
to come and free him tomorrow.
on her pillow thoughts stand in line
laid in the soil like flower seeds
shoots and sprouts and winds around
she understands nothing at all
hours feel like days
and weeks a thousand years
came to look back
to a world of yesterday
Jesus and Josefine
homeless heartache
but Jesus makes Josefine
believe in miracles
when she wavers
Jesus and Josefine
faithless time machine
the tempter's concubine
she needs miracles
and love
when she wavers
Uh, sorry.
- May I ask something?
- What now?
Those galleys,
when will I be sent off?
When the sun is at zenith, and there are no
more shadows on that column there, -
- then we ship you to the galleys,
and we won't see you until …
… until you become
old and gray-haired, -
- and your biceps are
as thick as tree trunks.
- Did you hear that?
- I'll come up with something.
I hope so too.
I'm not going out on those galleys.
- Are you talking to yourself?
- I have to run now.
(the phone buzzes)
Do you want a bun?
- Is something wrong?
- No no.
Hey, Josefine.
Cheer up. Spruce in your hair.
Try smelling them. Good, right?
Just take a couple
with you to school, okay?
- Are you leaving already?
- Oskar and I agreed to meet early.
Then we can rehearse the nativity play.
That's a bit strange,
because Oskar's mom just called.
And Oskar had called and said
that he was sleeping over at our place.
- Isn't that strange?
- He was supposed to sleep here.
But then he slept at Emilie's.
- Oh, are you upset about it?
- No no, it's totally fine.
(doorbell)
(Thorsen snoring)
Is that you, Josefine?
Good morning, Thorsen.
Nice work.
Who says it's a good morning?
Why are you here so early?
We have the first hours off, so I
wanted to finish the glitter pictures.
You do that, but don't
wake me up this early another time.
- I've been working all night.
- Sorry.
- Hi.
- Oh no, not her again.
- I was waiting.
- It couldn't be sooner.
- What about your little brother?
- I've come up with a genius plan.
Leave me and Simon out of it.
We all have to help,
otherwise Oskar ends up in the galleys.
We'll all help.
They smell good.
Now now, don't eat any.
We need them. Come here.
(Josefine whispers)
So the shadow isn't so tall anymore,
huh, miracle worker?
When the centurion comes,
we'll head out.
- Yeah, after we've had lunch.
— Yeah.
- Do you get seasick easily?
- Why?
- We'll cure that soon enough.
- After a couple years in the galleys.
Ha ha, very funny.
- What are you doing?
- We're opening a bakery here in Nazareth.
Would you like samples of
our new Nazareth buns? Free.
- They smell really good. Come here.
- No, the Romans don't pay that well.
- Yeah, let's give them to someone else.
- Hey, you. Come here with those buns.
They're confiscated.
They belong to the Roman Empire.
- Aren't you going to catch them first?
- What?
Come back! Come on!
- Josefine, Jesus.
- Hi, Oskar.
- How do we get this up?
- What's stronger than iron now?
- Oh, cool.
- You have many strange things up north.
Cover your eyes.
Now you're going to see miracles.
(cell phone rings)
— Hi, dad.
- Hi. Did you take all the buns?
- Wasn't I allowed to?
- Not all of them, right?
- I was supposed to bring them to school.
- I had a meeting with my publisher.
I was supposed to bring samples.
- Get me out of here.
- Bye bye, dad.
(phone buzzes)
I hope they tasted good.
Thanks, Josefine …. and Jesus.
What's that noise?
What's going on here, huh?
— Nothing.
- You just stay here, okay.
Freeing a rebel is considered
a great crime here in the Roman Empire.
We'll have a hard time looking away
from a couple of crucifixions here.
Run!
What is it? You can make fire!
Help! Save me!
I'll make sure not to
tell anyone anything.
Otherwise the sky will fall
down on your head.
- Are the Romans after you?
- We got rid of them.
- Bloody brilliant.
- Thanks. Well done.
- Thanks for the help.
- We all have to help each other, right?
— Right?
— Yeah.
Jesus of Nazareth.
It's pretty big to have met you.
I'm also glad to have
met you, Oskar, the boy from the North.
The boy from the North?
Are you then the girl from the North?
Oskar has a gift for you.
Give him the mobile phone.
You can just tell your parents,
you lost it.
Thanks for the help. Here.
- Thanks.
- There's not much battery left.
You just ask to
have it charged up.
Yep, now it's charged.
Jesus, you rascal.
Where have you been all day?
I've bought boards,
but lacked someone to carry them.
- Sorry, Josef.
— Josef?
And who is that slob then?
Uh, Josef, this is Oskar.
Oskar, this is Josef.
Hey in the shed.
Ha, you didn't know that one, did you?
- Are you Josef?
— Yes.
- Josef of Abraham's lineage?
Abraham, David, Uriah, Solomon
and all the way down to me.
Jesus.
(knock on the door)
- Open up in the name of the Roman Empire!
- What do we do?
We hide in here,
- What now?
- Hurry up.
- That was pretty wild.
- Yeah, I'm getting used to it.
Thorsen.
(motorcycle noise)
He's probably out riding.
What now then?
- I think it should stay between us.
- Good idea.
Apart from you being captured,
wasn't it pretty fantastic?
- I don't really know.
- You're just jealous.
- It's dangerous to change the past.
- That's too wild.
The girl from the North. The one who taught
Jesus to perform miracles.
I've heard about her since
I was little, and it's just you.
Can't you see it's dangerous?
— Not really dangerous.
- Grotesquely dangerous.
- Yeah, and you're boring.
- I should destroy that nativity play.
You wouldn't dare do that.
Come on now.
(doorbell)
Josefine and Oskar,
You can come out now.
Josefine and Oskar.
- Hi.
- How did those buns taste?
— Totally wild.
Since I didn't come
to the meeting at the publisher's,
- maybe you could help me
come up with a name for those buns?
We called them Nazareth buns.
Just like the ones Jesus' friends used
when they were to free the boy from the North.
— Yeah.
- It's very Christmassy too, right?
Then you could drink Nazareth juice with it.
That's a really good idea.
Dad, is it dangerous
to change the past?
Whether it's dangerous?
Well, I actually don't know.
There were plenty of things
I'd like to change.
- You just can't do that.
- But if you could.
Then you could prevent wars,
and people from being killed.
- Then everyone could wear elf hats.
- Of course it's dangerous.
- Elf hats aren't dangerous.
- Stop with the elf hat stuff.
How dangerous?
Even the smallest change in the past
can completely change people's lives.
How?
Once I biked over
a piece of glass, and my bike got a flat tire.
- By chance, a young guy came by.
- And that was Dad.
I know that story.
What's special about it?
If I hadn't run over the glass,
I wouldn't have met your dad.
And we wouldn't be sitting here.
You two would never have been born.
Dear God. Thanks because Oskar
was saved, and everything is okay.
I'll try not to change
too much in the past.
- At least not in a way that matters.
- Who wants a whack on the head?
That's you, if you don't
lie down and go to sleep now.
Because I don't want to miss
going down to Jesus. Amen.