Are you comfortably seated in front of the TV?
Are you ready for a real Christmas story?
Okay.
Oskar has been taken prisoner.
The Romans want to send him to the galleys.
When the sun is at its zenith, and there are no
more shadows on that pillar there, -
- we ship you off to the galleys.
Armed with Thorsen's pruning shears,
Josefine heads to Nazareth.
Simon and Judas lure the Romans away
with the help of Jesper's buns.
- We're opening a bakery here in Nazareth.
- Would you like to taste our Nazareth buns?
Your Nazareth buns
are hereby confiscated.
- Shouldn't you catch them first?
- What? Come back!
Josefine and Jesus free Oskar
with the pruning shears.
- The Romans' centurion surprises them.
— You stay here.
Freeing a rebel we consider
a great crime.
Run!
But when he sees Jesus make fire,
he falls to his knees and surrenders.
- Oskar greets Josef.
- Hi in the shed. You didn't know that one.
- And gives Jesus his mobile as thanks.
- A thousand thanks.
Oskar asks Josefine
not to change the past.
- Can't you see it's dangerous?
- It's too dangerous.
— Not really dangerous.
- Grotesquely dangerous.
Josefine says she'll try,
but she can't promise it.
on her pillow thoughts stand in line
laid in the soil like flower seeds
they shoot up and sprout and twist around
she understands nothing at all
hours feel like days
and weeks a thousand years
came to look back
to a world of yesterday
Jesus and Josefine
homeless heartache
but Jesus gets Josefine
to believe in miracles
when she wavers
Jesus and Josefine
faithless time machine
the tempter's concubine
she needs miracles
and love too
when she wavers
Josefine,
Uh.
(motorcycle noise)
Josefine,
- Josefine?
- Wish me luck at the publisher's.
- Take care of your back now.
- It doesn't weigh much.
- Can't you hear it?
- Hear what?
It's like someone
is calling my name.
— I can't hear anyone.
- I think it's Jesus.
- Why?
- She's been calling for him all night.
Jesus! And now he's coming back.
- That doesn't fit.
- Aren't you inviting Jesus home?
- I'd like to meet him.
- No, forget about that.
What's up with that Jesus? Is it because
he's 17 and a juvenile delinquent?
- What's wrong?
- Weren't you supposed to leave?
- Yeah, see you.
- Good luck.
(beep)
Hi.
My parents were just so dim-witted.
Hello?
That's too wild. We're in the Bible.
I'm the boy from the North.
- Him, whom Jesus set free.
- It was me who got you free.
- You're not going back down there, right?
- Why not?
- You could kill Jesus.
- Why would I kill him?
If the Romans got hold of him
and killed him as a boy.
- So what?
- Then the Bible wouldn't have been written.
- Aren't you exaggerating?
- We have to destroy that nativity play.
It's far too dangerous.
But I want to be allowed to go down to
Jesus one last time and say goodbye.
- What's so funny?
- That I've met the real Joseph.
I know how he should be played.
What kind of little rascal are you?
Dave's in the shed.
I am Joseph of Abraham's lineage.
You know, Abraham, David, Uriah,
Solomon and all the way to me.
Yeah, sorry, I'm interrupting, but…
- Was that why you were gone yesterday?
- What do you mean?
- To rewrite your roles.
- We think there should be more action.
As long as you don't change the story,
it's fine.
Josefine!
Josefine, come see. There's
a weird guy calling for you.
Josefine!
- He's freezing, he needs to come in the warm.
- One moment.
- Jesus.
- I knew I'd find you.
- Hi, little brother.
- You're not all there.
If this is the land to the North,
then it's cold and strange.
- We'll start by going over to your place.
- We'll go down and send him back.
I don't want to be sent back.
I want to see where you live.
Come.
- I saw boxes rolling with people in them.
- Those are cars.
How far are we from Galilee?
About 2,000 years.
I don't get that.
Jesus, you've come to the future.
Are you from God's kingdom or Satan's?
From Denmark. A completely ordinary country.
- We're not in Hell?
- I'll show you something.
Hey, Jesus. Try this,
My friends need to see me in this.
Thanks, little brother.
I'm not her little brother.
I'm her friend.
- I'm three months older.
- Sorry, I ended up lying.
That's okay.
I forgive you.
So we should probably go down to Thorsen, right?
— We have to stop by the church first.
- The church?
He should at least see
his father's house, right?
(organ music)
Is that God speaking?
That's Poulsen,
who's practicing Christmas hymns,
- And is this God's house?
- Yes, this is God's house.
Oh no, the cross!
- Why is there a crucified man here?
- You'll have to figure this out yourself.
- Sorry.
- I can see who it is.
The man the Romans executed in front of
Nazareth. It looks just like him.
- It shows how malicious they are.
- Yes, exactly.
But now I really want to
go home to Nazareth.
"Closed due to freedom"?
Thorsen.
It's right in the middle of opening hours, though.
(motorcycle noise)
- He's roaring around on his motorcycle.
- He's cheeky.
- He's pretty cringy.
- But also quite nice.
So I can't go home at all?
Yes, if you sleep at my place tonight,
we'll get you home tomorrow.
- Okay.
- Come on.
I was about to get into the Guinness
Book of Records with the smallest Christmas heart.
But then my dad opened the window,
and guess what, it blew away.
I want to be in the Guinness Book of Records too.
So it's just about practicing,
and it will surely work out.
- Hi.
- Hi, Josefine.
- Oh, you have guests with you.
— Yes.
My name is Louise,
I'm Josefine's mom.
Uh, this is Jesus.
The one I've talked so much about.
- What's wrong with dad?
- Yeah, he…
They weren't thrilled with the baking book. There
were too many recipes for buns.
So now he's got a bad back.
Jesper, say hi to Jesus.
Oh, so you're Jesus. Hi hi.
We've talked quite a bit about you…
Jesper.
Why doesn't he have
that kind of clothes on?
Well, it's because
Jesus is a smart boy, right?
Mom, can Jesus sleep here tonight?
Jesus forgot his keys,
and his parents are away traveling.
- Yes, of course he can.
- Can you play Kalaha?
Yes, Jesus wants to play
in a bit. Come on.
- Have you seen Jesus today?
- He hasn't been here at all.
I told his mom
that he was probably with you.
He's probably with Josefine.
Could be, if we find him,
we earn a silver coin.
- Judas, you always think about money.
- Boys.
Warn Jesus.
He is in great danger.
- Where is he?
- I don't know.
He is distant from me.
But I hear a strange word.
Ju. JU...
Christmas heart.
- That's a Christmas heart.
- It looks like what you drew in the sand.
Yes, look. Then you can put
candy in it and hang it on the tree.
- What tree?
- The Christmas tree.
- What is a Christmas tree?
- Don't you celebrate Christmas at all, Jesus?
Yes yes, he does.
It's just a different Christmas.
- So without a Christmas tree.
- Is that in South America or Spain?
- In Nazareth.
- I know you live on Nazareth Road.
But you and your family,
where are you from?
Jesus isn't exactly a normal name
around these parts.
- Normally one could well … ow!
- Dad!
- Ow, ow, ow!
- What's happening?
It's the back.
I'm going to the chiropractor now.
- I'll call a taxi.
- Ow, ow, ow!
Uh … what is it again?
Our, yes.
Josephine's dad.
In God's name, heal that man.
- It takes a bit more than that.
- Stand up. You are healed.
I've had it 1000 times.
I need to go to the chiropractor.
Dad, stand up.
Wow, that's wild.
- It's completely gone now.
- That's why they call him Jesus.
I mean, Jesus with the magic hands.
No, come on.
- You promised to play Kalaha.
- In a bit.
They sure got
something to think about, huh?
- Was that wrong of me?
- No, that was fantastic.
You think so?
Shall we pray together?
Dear God.
Thank you for letting me sleep here tonight.
Thanks to Josefine for being so sweet.
Thanks to Lukas for a good game of Kalaha.
- May he get better at losing.
- I can handle losing.
Lukas, sleep.
I'm praying that I may
get home safely tomorrow. Amen.