Are you sitting comfortably in front of the TV?
Are you ready for a real Christmas story?
Jesus has discovered
the manger's secret -
- and suddenly stands in Thorsen's shop.
Jesus appears in the schoolyard.
Josefine and Oskar
hurry off with Jesus.
We're switching to you.
They show him the church.
Jesus sees the crucified man É
Why is there a crucified man
in my father's house?
É but doesn't understand,
it's himself.
That's the man
the Romans executed.
Oskar wants to get Jesus home
to Nazareth as quickly as possible.
But when they get to Thorsen's shop,
it's closed.
- "Closed due to freedom"?
- Can't I go home then?
Yes, if you sleep at my place tonight.
Josefine invites Jesus home,
and the family greets Jesus.
Jesper and Louise think
he's an ordinary boy.
Is that you, Jesus? Hi hi.
Jesper's back gives out,
and Jesus heals him on the spot.
- In God's name, heal that man.
- It's completely gone now.
That's why we call him Jesus.
Jesus with the magic hands.
on her pillow thoughts stand in line
laid in the earth like flower seeds
shoots and sprouts and twines around
she understands nothing at all
hours feel like days
and weeks a thousand years
came to look back
to a world of yesterday
Jesus and Josefine
homeless heartache
Jesus makes Josefine
believe in miracles
when she wavers
Jesus and Josefine
faithless time machine
the tempter's concubine
she needs miracles
and love
when she wavers
Jesus!
Something bad has happened to him. Jesus
would never disappear on a Sabbath.
Maybe he's out thinking about life.
I'd do the same if I
were told I was God's son.
I asked him to fix this
yesterday. Now I'll do it myself.
I'll go out and look for him.
Stay here if he shows up.
Pray that he hasn't been
beaten to death by the Romans.
Those couple of Romans here in town
wouldn't hurt a fly. Or É
- Haven't you baked at all today?
- No É Today it's the baker's bread.
- How's the back?
- Pretty good.
- It was Jesus who healed you.
- No, it wasn't.
It was like it was a nerve
that had gotten pinched in the lower back.
- Right when he touched me, I think É
- Maybe Jesus has healing powers.
You should try to be
a bit more open.
- Good morning.
- Good morning. Did you sleep well?
Is that sabbath bread?
The baker just called it filone bread.
- Did you remember to bless it?
- No.
We don't usually do that here.
My wife is a priest, sure, but É
May I just bless it?
If you think it's going to
taste better, you're welcome to.
Blessed are you, Lord,
our God, -
- King of the universe, who brings forth
bread from the earth. Amen.
- Do you always do that before you eat?
- No, my father usually does it.
Or my stepfather.
My father is in Heaven.
- So your father is dead?
- Nah, my father is God.
And so your stepfather is Joseph?
That's just what he's called.
Not to butt in, and it's Christmas
and pine needles in the hair and all that,
- Do you really believe you're God's son?
- Come on, let's go now. You need to go home.
Jesus É.
I just want to say, it was
really positive meeting you.
Have a safe trip home.
Give me that bread there,
You shouldn't have said that about
God being your father.
- Why would I lie?
- To avoid stupid questions.
I don't mind them.
Except if they're from my mom.
Have you thought about telling
your mom where you've been?
- I don't think so.
- But then you're lying.
I'll just say I met an angel.
So I'm not lying.
You're an angel.
Well, before I leave,
I want to say goodbye to Oskar.
Jesus, wait.
Hi, Oskar.
Are you saying goodbye to Jesus?
God, what happened?
- Josefine the degu is dead.
- Oh no.
It was just lying completely still.
I want to bury it out in the front yard.
- Why don't you bring it back to life?
- I don't think I'm allowed to.
- You do that when you get older.
- Do I raise a dead degu?
No, but a dead man.
His name was Lazarus, I think. Right?
- I don't know any Lazarus.
- Do you want to hear it?
- Yes.
- Hold on. I need to find it.
Are you É. Are you Joseph? The carpenter?
Sorry, is it something with my son?
Your son is the boy
with fire from his finger, right?
I don't know.
He can do some strange things.
Well, then it's your son
I've met.
You haven't taken him prisoner, have you?
No no, we could never dream of
taking the boy prisoner.
We certainly don't dare.
I've come to ask
if you can repair that one.
It's the lid that's wrong with.
- Not today, it's the Sabbath.
- I'm going to Caesarea tomorrow.
I want to take my travel chest
with me home.
Be glad my wife is out.
She would be furious.
I'll pay well.
- I have no more wood.
- The manger. What about this manger?
- That's excellent wood. We'll use it.
- That's where my son lay when he was little.
Excellent. The boy with fire
out of his finger lay there.
I absolutely must use that wood
for my coffin.
(coins clink in the purse)
- It'll be ready tomorrow.
- Good. Excellent.
A lot of people are crying because
Lazarus is dead.
Then you look up to heaven and say:
"Father, I thank you
because you heard me." Then you shout:
"Lazarus! Come out!"
And then a living Lazarus comes.
- Do I really do all that?
- You become quite fantastic as an adult.
- Then my mother is right.
- I've also started to believe in you.
Me too.
Josefine dear, open your eyes.
I ask you in God's name.
That's too wild.
Father, I thank you,
because you have heard me.
- Thanks, Jesus.
- I didn't even know I could.
- What else does that book say?
- It doesn't say anything special.
Doesn't it say anything about
when I die?
- No. Why would it?
- I just lived so long ago.
- I must be dead now.
- It actually doesn't say anything about that.
Quite strange.
But it says something about É
that you become very wise and old.
Does it really say that?
But now I really want to go home.
We have to get him past Thorsen.
Hey, Oskar.
What can I help you with?
I just wanted to ask
if Josefine was here?
Nah. I haven't seen her today.
- What are you doing?
- Sorry.
- No, what a mess.
- Sorry. It wasn't on purpose.
No no. It's okay.
You can
help me clean up, right?
- Then goodbye, Jesus.
- You're coming tomorrow, right? See you.
You just have to push.
Nothing happens.
Joseph?
What are you doing?
You're not working, are you?
- No! It's the Sabbath.
- Good. I thought for a momentÉ
I was standing thinking about Jesus.
I wonder where he is.
I've been all over Nazareth. No one
has seen or heard anything of him.
- Just hope he hasn't been kidnapped.
- Who would kidnap him?
There are many evil forces that will
do anything to stop God's son.
There. That's good, Oskar.
That's good.
What the heck?
Hi, so you are here after all. I just
told Oskar you weren't here.
We were supposed to find costumes for him here
for the nativity play.
Who's this guy?
It's just É Jens.
Jens from our class.
He's going to play grown-up Jesus.
Hi, Jens.
What do you say to this one, huh?
That's nice.
We're off now. Bye bye.
Watch out that the nativity play doesn't go to your
heads. You don't think about anything else.
- And it didn't work at all?
- There must be an explanation.
It's Thorsen who did it.
Now Jesus is stuck in the present.
So he can't do all that stuff in the Bible.
- Why would Thorsen do that?
- Because he doesn't like Jesus.
- So can I not go home?
Ñ We'll figure out how.
- If we can.
- Of course we can.
You'll sleep here until tomorrow,
and then we'll try again.
I'm thinking of
dropping that baking book.
- I don't know if that's really me.
- You have to make your baking book.
- You think so?
- Yes. It's a smashing good idea.
I believe in it.
You might be right.
- Hi.
Hi, Jesus.
I thought you'd left.
He was supposed to.
But the flight was delayed.
Yeah, Jesus' parents É
were on a trip to Egypt.
- Egypt?
- It's fine, you're here.
But I need some peace to
write my sermon.
My mom says,
that there's only peace in Heaven.
Here on Earth we have to live in discord.
Does she say that?
That's É
That's actually not so dumb.
Simple and É straightforward.
You, Jesus É I'll borrow that
for my sermon, if that's okay.
- Okay.
Ñ Thanks.
Come.
I pray you take care of Josefine
and her house -
- and help me safely home
to Nazareth tomorrow. Amen.
It would otherwise be nice,
if you could stay here.
Then I can't do the things
in the big book. What is it I do?
All sorts. Heals the sick,
makes the blind see and that stuff,
- Think, that they wrote it down.
- Me and Oskar are in it too.
Ñ The Bible has actually gotten better.
-Ñ Has it?
- I want to be in the Bible too.
- Lukas, be quiet and sleep.
- Goodnight, Josefine.
- Goodnight, Jesus.
I'll get you home tomorrow.