Are you comfortably seated in front of the TV?
Are you ready for a real Christmas story?
In Nazareth, Joseph and Mary
are looking for Jesus.
Good morning.
They don't know he's traveled 2,000 years
forward in time to present-day Denmark.
The baker called it a filone bread.
At Josefine's
Jesus blesses the bread.
If you think it's going to
taste better, you're most welcome.
Blessed are you, Lord,
our God …
He tells them
that his real father is God.
Do you really believe you're God's son?
Before Jesus goes home to Nazareth,
they will say goodbye to Oskar.
Oskar is sad.
Josefine-Dego is dead,
Josefine gets Jesus to
bring it back to life.
Josefine-Dego, open your eyes.
I beg you in God's name.
In Nazareth, Joseph gets a visit from
the Roman centurion.
He wants Joseph to
repair a wooden chest.
I don't have any more wood.
The manger. That's excellent wood.
We'll just use that.
Joseph decides
to use the wood from the manger.
At Thorsen's, Jesus discovers
that the nativity scene isn't working.
It's Thorsen who did it.
- Can't I go home?
— We'll figure out how.
on her pillow thoughts stand in line
laid in the earth like flower seeds
shoots and sprouts and winds around
she understands nothing at all
hours feel like days
and weeks a thousand years
came to look back
to a world of yesterday
Jesus and Josefine
homeless heartache
Jesus gets Josefine
to believe in miracles
when she wavers
Jesus and Josefine
faithless time machine
the tempter's concubine
she needs miracles
also for love
when she wavers
- Where is Jesus?
- That's a very authentic recipe.
- How much flour do you use?
- Just what's needed.
That's the kind of recipe
I can understand.
Jesus is teaching me to bake flatbread
like in the old days of Jesus.
That goes in my cookbook.
No! You mustn't put it on the
hotplate. You need a pan.
My mother
always puts it on the stone oven.
Come.
Jesus …… How do your parents feel about
you calling yourself Jesus?
- It's them who call him that.
- No, an angel gave me the name.
- Can I meet your parents?
- No.
- Now I'm talking to Jesus.
- There was something you were going to show me.
Josefine. We need to
talk about this.
- What are we going to talk about?
- Your friend Jesus.
He's a nice guy and really sweet,
but he's not right in the head.
It doesn't help to support
him in that. He needs help.
- I am helping him.
- It smells so good here.
You know what? I asked Jesus...
No flour on the priest's robe.
Jesus wants to come to church.
That's the right place for a boy
who thinks he is called Jesus.
Jesper, Jesus can't help it
that he has special powers.
Special powers?
The boy is raving mad.
He's trying to
teach Lukas to walk on water.
Are you taking him to the service?
What if your mom says,
he ends up on the cross?
Who says he ends up on that cross?
Maybe we can prevent it.
- We're not getting involved. Jesus needs to go home.
- He will. Just relax.
- I just need to figure out how.
- I went so far, and then I fell in.
(the organ plays)
- Now my mom is going up to preach.
- Why aren't there more people here?
- Because it's only Sunday.
- The synagogue is always full.
At Christmas it's packed here.
Christmas is the time of the heart.
We cozy up in the glow of the Advent candle.
But we must not forget that when Jesus
was born in a stable in Bethlehem, -
- there was no peace in the world.
Just like there is no peace in our time.
I was reminded of that yesterday,
when my daughter's friend wisely said:
There is always strife on Earth,
only in Heaven is there peace.
That is the hope Jesus gives us
with his birth... and with his death.
But we must not close our eyes
and just wait to get to Heaven.
For Jesus was not afraid
to walk on earth, even though it burned.
Yes. And he's sitting right here.
Honestly, shouldn't we go?
You! Son of Man.
Your father wants you back,
but the manger is gone.
"The manger is gone."
What if I never get home?
We'll get you home.
Even though the manger is gone,
it should still work.
- Then you just come out another way.
- What if it's broken?
- What do you mean?
- If the Romans destroyed our house.
If only we could call and ask.
- We can.
- Don't you have your mobile?
- Simon and Judas have it.
- Why didn't you say so earlier?
Are Simon and Judas your friends?
(mobile rings)
No, it's there. Let me just.
- It's Judas.
- Hi, Judas. It's Josefine.
- Hi. Where is Jesus?
- Right here. Try saying hi.
- Hi.
- Ask if he's coming home soon.
- Are you coming home soon?
- I hope so.
Go into the stable
and look for an old manger.
That's the one from Bethlehem.
- Why do we have to do that?
- Just do it now, and call back.
- How do you call back?
- Press the green button three times.
Bye bye.
So let's cross our fingers. We have to get
down to Thorsen before he closes.
- What's happening at Thorsen's?
- Nothing. You need to go home now.
I'm hurrying back.
Come on, Lukas.
That's really a keepsake
worth taking with you.
You'll have to pay a little extra.
I got scolded by my wife
for working on the Sabbath.
I had to hide
that I used wood from my son's manger.
I'll gladly pay extra for the wood -
- from the boy
with fire out of the finger's manger.
And don't say
that a Roman never pays his debt.
- Have they called?
- No, not yet.
(phone rings)
- It's Jesus.
- Your dad used the manger for a lid.
- He sold it to the Romans.
- Then I can't come home.
- Hello? Why is the manger so important?
- Because I need it.
You'll have to get the manger
and put it back in the stable.
We can't get it from the Romans.
- Can't you throw a stink bomb?
- What's that?
Throw something that smells bad.
Then you clear the joint.
- Then you grab the lid meanwhile.
- But it's dangerous.
It's an order from God.
Jesus says
it's a direct order from God.
Call when you've done it.
Remember those fish my dad
brought? They've started rotting.
Hurry up.
Wha' …
Ugh, what a stench!
Can you get rid of that smell!
I'm trying to pack something.
Fools! Imbeciles!
This is an outrage against
the entire Roman Empire.
How could you let it pass
without intervening?
It's the kind of uprising
we're here to crush!
And you let yourselves get taken in by
some rotten fish.
- But, centurion …
- I don't want to hear any more excuses!
Get those fish removed!
And go take a bath.
Damn terror attacks.
Good thing I'm going home.
- It fits really well.
- Tell me, what are you doing?
- We're putting the manger together.
- But I just sold it.
- What did you just sell?
- He destroyed Jesus' manger.
- But now we've made it.
- What do you have?
- I got good money for it.
- It's my last memory of Jesus.
How nicely you've made it, boys.
Put it in the stable, Judas.
Joseph, you're coming with me right now.
We have something to talk about. Now!
It's Simon. The manger is repaired,
Judas is putting it in the stable.
Fine, Simon. See you.
- That's it. Now I can go home.
- Then we just need to go down to Thorsen.
You have to remember your tunic …
and your sandals.
Josefine, there's something
I want to ask you about.
Down in the church
your mother said something about my death.
Yes,
- What's with my death?
- There's nothing.
- But how do I die?
- Like an ordinary old man.
(there's a knock on the door)
- Hello. Is that you, Jesus?
- Uh … yes. Jesus of Nazareth.
Your parents are away traveling?
- Nah, I think they're home.
- Come with us. We need to talk to you.
- You can't do that.
- What?
It's okay, Josefine.
I've written the history of flatbread
into my baking book.
- Jesus has been taken by the police!
- It was me who called them.
- Is he going to jail?
- No, now social services will take over.
Why did you do it?
The boy thinks he's Jesus
and doesn't know where he lives.
His parents are away traveling.
That's irresponsible.
- The authorities need to know.
- He was on his way home to his parents.
You've ruined everything.
Dear God, you must save Jesus, -
- so he doesn't go to jail
or to an orphanage.
And I'm also praying that the nativity play
works, so he can come home.
- What nativity play?
- Lie down and sleep.
- Where is Thorsen's shop?
- Nowhere. Sleep!
Now I just hope
no more accidents happen. Amen.