Are you comfortably seated in front of the TV?
Are you ready for a real Christmas story?
- Jesus has traveled 2000 years into the future.
- Not on the stove!
- He lives with Josefine.
- Use a pan.
- My mom puts it on the stone oven.
- Jesper is worried about Jesus.
He's sweet, but not well.
He needs help.
The manger doesn't work.
Your father wants you back,
but the manger is gone.
Jesus can't come home.
Jesus calls Nazareth and gets Simon
and Judas to look for the manger.
They discover that Joseph sold the wood
from the manger to the Romans.
I got scolded
for working on the Sabbath.
I had to hide,
I used wood from my son's manger.
Jesus orders them to
recreate the manger.
- But it's dangerous.
- Say, it's an order from God.
Jesus says,
it's a direct order from God.
- It succeeds …
- Are you the Jesus?
But before Jesus can leave,
he is picked up by two policemen.
- You can't do that.
- It's okay, Josefine.
When Josefine comes home, Jesper says
he reported Jesus to the police.
It was me,
who told them about Jesus.
You've just ruined everything,
on her pillow thoughts line up
laid in the soil like flower seeds
shoots and sprouts and winds around
she understands nothing at all
hours feel like days
and weeks a thousand years
came to look back
to a world of yesterday
Jesus and Josefine
homeless heartache
Jesus makes Josefine
believe in miracles
when she wavers
Jesus and Josefine
faithless time machine
the tempter's concubine
she needs miracles
and love
when she wavers
- Have you found out where Jesus is?
- I'm on hold. They find the log.
A kringle?
Why did you ask the police
to go after him?
- He thinks he's Jesus.
- That's why he shouldn't be abducted.
He hasn't been abducted.
You're completely blinded by him.
As if you were brainwashed.
Maybe you're in love.
Love makes you blind.
Wait, now he's there.
Hello? Yes.
Okay. Yes, that's clear.
Should I just call tonight then?
I will. Thanks a thousand. Bye.
Now listen here.
Jesus stayed overnight at Solhuset.
It's a residential institution for young people
who are having a hard time.
That's where he'll stay,
until they find his family.
- How long will it take?
- Until they find out something more.
They were right.
She's completely crazy about him.
Aren't you supposed to be in school?
Pine needles in your hair, right?
Have a pretzel.
- We just need to get him out of Solhuset.
- The hardest part will be getting in.
We'll have to smuggle him out.
We don't need to smugle him out.
- Why not?
- Once we're in, we'll get him out.
I have a plan. We'll go down to
Thorsen first and then find Solhuset.
Hi, Oskar and Josefine.
I was just thinking about you.
I want to expand the shop
and need employees.
- How will you make room for that?
- There's plenty of space behind the door.
- What about getting more customers first?
- After the expansion, they'll come flocking.
They can't compete with my good offers.
Don't you want to be part of it?
- We go to school.
- Oh. What are you doing here then?
- The phone rang.
- Can we borrow your nativity scene?
Why should I lend it to you
when you don't want to work for me?
The guy who makes our props
has stalled.
I'd do that too.
But then we said we knew someone
who had the most beautiful nativity scene.
Aren't you thinking a bit too much
about nativity scenes?
Our teacher Jytte is really into it.
Is there anything I can't stand more
than people named Jytte.
- They're insanely crazy.
- Can we borrow it then?
- Then you'll get some pretzels too.
- Pretzels?
Okay. Just take it then.
But you have to promise to take good care
of it. It's very fragile.
Thanks,
Can you tell me
what that costume means to you?
That's what we wear where I'm from.
- Where are you from?
- Nazareth.
- Why do you think that?
- Because that's where I live.
- How long have you lived there?
- Since we moved from Egypt.
King Herod wanted to kill you,
and when he died, you moved home?
Do you also know
what happens to you later?
I raise a dead man
named Lazarus, -
- and help many sick people.
- Do you feel like God?
- My mother says I'm God's son.
- How do you get along with mom and dad?
- Good.
Do they have problems?
Do they drink? Fight?
My mom thinks
Joseph drinks a bit too much wine.
What do you think yourself, Jesus?
Is he unpleasant to you?
It can be annoying
always having to turn water into wine.
I don't think
you have it so easy, Jesus.
When you don't have it easy, sometimes you
feel like being someone else.
Someone who has mighty powers.
I need to make some phone calls,
so you can consider, -
- if you want to tell me your
real name when I come back.
It should be here.
Solhuset.
Yes?
We were going to visit one,
who's called Jesus.
- Hi, Jesus.
- Hi. Good to see you.
- Are they strict?
- There's one who asks and asks.
A psychologist.
A bit like a priest,
just without God.
- Put on the tunic.
- You have to go home now.
Josefine, hurry up now.
- Okay, so we'll pray it works.
- Thanks for the help.
- See you,
- No, you won't!
- It will end badly. It has to stop.
- Just a lightning-quick visit.
Shall we say goodbye then?
Goodbye, Jesus.
He's coming now!
Goodbye,
Where is Jesus?
He's gone.
Josef,
Boo!
- Jesus!
- Oh, my God.
Thank you, God,
for bringing my son back.
- I think you've grown.
- You look good.
I've found out
it's true, what you said.
- That I'll become a great man one day.
- How did you find that out?
I've looked into the coming times.
- Have you seen God's kingdom?
- Probably not.
I've seen a time
when I was remembered as God's son.
So you know it?
How good that is.
You can still help your father
in the workshop?
I have to go out and help
the weak on the roads.
One day I raise Lazarus.
I grow old and die of happiness.
Well
a
What about us then?
Will we be remembered too?
- You can believe that.
- Josef …
We should destroy that nativity scene.
We promised to return it.
When you promise something, you keep it.
- But still.
- Good, you came.
I've actually regretted that I
ever lent it to you.
It should on no account
fall into the wrong hands.
I can actually reveal to you, -
- that this nativity scene is magical.
Imagine, is that true?
It sounds like it doesn't
come as a surprise to you.
Have you used it for something
you shouldn't have?
I can do anything.
We're all gods, right?
Ouch, you got me there.
You see…
… it's not for everyone
to be fiddling with this.
And I am the guardian of the nativity set.
I must ensure
that no one misuses its magic.
What can it do?
If you know it, you know it,
and otherwise you won't find out.
- Was there anything else?
- Nah.
Yeah … Do you think you could
do me and Oskar a favor?
That depends on what.
You have to call Solhuset and say
that you are Jesus' father.
- God knows I'm not.
- Not that Jesus.
Just say that you are the father of the boy
who plays Jesus in the nativity play, -
- and that he is completely normal,
just likes to act.
What do I get in return?
You know what?
You can come work for me
when I expand the shop.
- Okay?
- Yeah yeah. Right?
- Great. Bye then.
- Bye.
He is pretty weird,
that Thorsen.
- Maybe he's Satan.
- Satan?
- He's not that weird.
- Isn't he?
Okay. He knows that you can travel
to Nazareth with the nativity set.
We have to stay far away from him.
You're just scared that
I'll go down to Jesus again.
I'll make sure not to do that.
But Thorsen is decent enough.
He helped us at least
with calling Solhuset.
- Hi, Jesus!
- Hi, Jesus. Are you okay?
I'm completely okay.
- Thanks for the help.
- No problem.
- Won't you play with us?
- I just need to think.
Because now I know
that I am humanity's savior.
So you'll never play with us again?
Okay. One single game.
Come on with it, Jesper.
- What?
- With a "sorry".
- Why should I say sorry?
- You wanted to get Jesus into the orphanage.
Why should I say sorry?
The boy was just acting.
It's him who should say sorry to me.
They were pretty confused down at Solhuset
when they had talked to his father.
- You could just have asked me.
- Yeah, you could. So say sorry.
But okay, sorry.
Jesus is at least good at
walking on water.
Exactly, Lukas. With a bit of good imagination
and some grit in the hair, anything can be done.
Dad?
Does Satan exist in reality?
Now stop it, Josefine.
Have you met him too now?
Oskar just thought that.
When we do something bad to others,
Satan plays a trick on us.
But he is not a person
one can meet.
- I'll sign under that.
- Okay. I'll tell Oskar.
Dear God. I'm glad
that Jesus came home.
And I know full well,
I shouldn't visit him again.
- But I miss him already.
- Look what I've made for Jesus.
- You can't give Jesus an elf hat.
— J0.
Lukas, it's too late now.
Jesus has gone home.
I want you to
take care of Jesus, okay? Amen.