Are you comfortably seated in front of the TV?
Are you ready for a real Christmas story?
Have you figured out where Jesus is?
Jesus has traveled 2000 years into the future
to present-day Denmark.
Jesper has reported Jesus
to the social authorities.
- He thinks he's Jesus.
- That's why he shouldn't be abducted.
Josefine and Oskar discover that Jesus
is at the residential institution Solhuset.
We need to go down to Thorsen
and then find Solhuset.
They visit Thorsen,
who wants to expand his business.
- I need employees.
- They borrow the nativity scene.
Promise me to take good care of it.
It's very fragile.
Over at Solhuset
a psychologist analyzes Jesus.
- Why do you think you're from Nazareth?
- Because that's where I live.
Josefine and Oskar
sneak in to see Jesus.
With the nativity scene, they get
Jesus sent home to Nazareth.
Shall we say goodbye then?
In Nazareth, Joseph and Mary
are happy to get Jesus back.
Thank you, God, for my son!
Jesus says that he now understands
what it means to be God's son.
Josefine and Oskar
return the nativity scene.
It's not everyone
who benefits from tinkering with it.
- I am the guardian of the nativity scene.
- Oskar thinks Thorsen is weird.
Maybe he's Satan.
on her pillow thoughts stand in line
laid in the soil like flower seeds
shoots and sprouts and winds around
she understands nothing at all
hours feel like days
and weeks a thousand years
came to look back
to a world of yesterday
Jesus and Josefine
homeless heartache
Jesus makes Josefine
believe in miracles
when she wavers
Jesus and Josefine
faithless time machine
the tempter's concubine
she needs miracles
and love
when she wavers
- They taste good.
- It's a super simple recipe.
- What do you have there?
- An elf hat for Jesus.
- Josefine can take it with her.
- I want to give it to him myself.
- It'll be hard, because he's gone.
- Home to Nazareth?
- Stop teasing her.
- It's dangerous to go around playing Jesus.
The last one who did it
ended up on the cross.
- We don't crucify people in Denmark.
- I'm traveling to Nazareth with his hat.
First, we two are heading
down to the kindergarten for a visit.
Are you taking a priest's ear with you?
What, darling?
- What are you thinking about?
- Jesus.
If you feel like inviting Jesus
home with you, you're very welcome to do that.
I don't think that'll happen for now.
What are you thinking about?
Josefine. I miss her.
Look! Over there! Lepers.
- Get lost!
- We don't want lepers here!
- Why do you say that?
- Do you want to get infected and become crippled?
- Judas is right, they can infect.
- I don't believe that.
Help us. You must help us.
Help us.
- Won't you?
- Okay.
Okay.
(angel choir)
Get up. You are healed now.
We are healed.
Thank you!
Thank you, you who can heal.
Thank you! It's a miracle,
- It's a miracle.
- We should open a doctor's clinic.
We can get rich!
No, Judas. There are some things
one doesn't do for money.
Quiet. Any questions
before we start rehearsing?
- Yes, Josefine.
- Why was Jesus crucified?
The nativity play is about
that he was born.
But it's a good question.
Jesus knew that he had to die.
It was part of God's plan.
Why?
He was crucified because we are cowards
and only think about ourselves.
Instead of avenging himself
he took the blame from us -
- and gave us hope of eternal life.
Three days after he died,
he rose again, you see.
And 40 days later he ascended to Heaven,
where he sits at God's right hand.
- What if that hadn't happened?
- Then Christianity wouldn't exist.
Then the world
would have looked completely different.
Now we're starting to rehearse.
There aren't many days until Christmas.
We need the soldiers over here.
Hello? I'd like to go to Nazareth.
How do I get to Nazareth?
(glockenspiel and angel choir)
Jesus?
My name is Joseph.
What kind of strange creature are you?
- Hi, my name is Luke.
- Hi.
- I have a nephew named Luke.
- Do you know where Jesus is?
He should help me plane
this, but he's probably outside.
Hi!
- Hi, Jesus!
- Luke, what are you doing here?
I have a gift for you.
You have to unwrap it.
You have to put it on.
Like this?
- NOW it's sitting properly.
- Okay.
- Who is that guy?
— Josefine's little brother.
Yeah, sorry, but …
Jesus … surely that's not how
we're gonna get a bite of bread?
- We haven't eaten for days.
- I have a cake.
- That won't fill them up.
— Can I just borrow that one?
(angel choir)
Thanks a lot.
That's fantastic.
Another miracle. Thanks a lot.
It was good that we got Jesus home.
Imagine if we could make Christianity
disappear.
I just don't feel like
I said a proper goodbye.
- Then send a text.
- Jesus can't text.
- Just don't go down there again.
- I promised.
(phone rings)
— Hi, dad.
- Hi. Have you seen Lukas?
- Why?
- He ran away from kindergarten.
He said
he wanted to give Jesus a gift.
He talked about one
named Thorsen. Do you know him?
- Is something wrong?
- Not at all.
- Hey, now Lukas is coming.
- That's good.
I was about to
get really nervous.
- Say hi and scold him for me.
- I will. Bye bye, dad.
- What's happening?
- Lukas traveled through the time portal.
We have to go to Jesus
and fetch him.
Wait a sec. Just look here.
"The little boy from the land to the North
had a hat for Jesus, -
- and he taught him to turn one loaf
into many."
He gave Jesus the elf hat.
Done with
changing the Bible story.
Call Jesus and make sure
he gets Lukas home.
- Do you mean it?
— Yes.
Call now.
How did you turn one loaf
into many?
We could get filthy rich. We could
bake bread for all of Jerusalem.
That's not what it's about.
Thanks for your bread, Lukas. You've
understood it's about giving.
- And spruce in the hair.
- Spruce in the hair?
Hi, Josefine. Yeah, he's here.
I'll take care of it. Talk later.
They want you to come home.
See you tomorrow. Come on.
Who is that?
And what do you look like?
- Lukas. He's coming with gifts.
- Lukas?
Oh, that cousin from Jerusalem?
- Yeah. And I have spruce in my hair.
— Yeah …
- So how did you get here?
- I traveled by time machine.
Camel caravan.
I'll take him down to the camels.
Yeah,
Then you have to say hi in Jerusalem …
…. Lukas.
- What are those camels?
- Come.
Are you scared of that thing with
dying on the cross?
What are you talking about? I die
as an old man with a long beard.
You'll get a long beard at least.
- Hi, Thorsen.
- Hi, Josefine.
- Have you been here earlier today?
- Nah.
No. I just got here too.
I've been out
clearing a deceased estate.
What do you say then? Now I can finally
get a cup of cappuccino.
Are you going to the back room?
No, not today.
I'm just picking up my little brother.
- Hi, Lukas.
- Hi, Josefine.
- I haven't seen you at all.
- Well, thanks for the ride.
Thanks, you too.
Well, we're going now.
Bye bye, Thorsen. See you.
You won't tell mom and dad
what we've been through, right?
What are you sitting there thinking about?
- Am I going to die on a cross someday?
- No.
What kind of nonsense is that?
Who said that?
You're not going to die on any cross.
Your father up there will take care of that.
You shall be king.
You shall save us all.
(angelic choir)
(thunder)
You can't just
leave the daycare all by yourself, right?
I was going to give Jesus my elf hat.
- Did he have some sweet parents?
- They were very sweet.
- Jesus has completely normal parents.
- Of course.
But I wasn't allowed to
ride the camels.
- Hi, Jesus.
- I've experienced something strange.
We have to meet tomorrow.
- I don't know if that's a good idea.
- We have to meet. I beg you.
Okay, then I'll come over
after school tomorrow.
- Who was that?
— Jesus.
Dear God.
I have to break my promise to Oskar.
Because tomorrow I'm going down to Jesus
for the last time.
- And I want to come.
- No, Lukas.
- One trip to Nazareth has to be enough.
- Aw!
I need to know,
why Jesus sounded so strange.
Just as long as nothing serious has happened to him. Amen.