Are you comfortably seated in front of the TV?
Are you ready for a real Christmas story?
Jesus is back in Nazareth. Josefine
has promised Oskar not to visit him.
Lukas has an elf hat for Jesus.
- Josefine can give it to him.
- I want to do it myself.
Lukas runs away from kindergarten
and makes his way to Thorsens' shop.
Lukas gives the elf hat to Jesus,
who has healed some lepers.
You have to put it on.
Josefine contacts Jesus
and gets him to send Lukas home.
- They want you home.
- I have to fetch my little brother.
- Hi, Lukas.
- Hi, Josefine.
In the evening, Jesus has a vision.
His hands begin to bleed.
Jesus calls Josefine
and wants to meet.
I've experienced something strange.
We have to meet tomorrow.
In her evening prayer, Josefine confesses
that she has to break her promise to Oskar -
- and travel to Jesus one last time.
- And I want to come along.
- One trip to Nazareth should be enough.
Aw!
I have to know
why Jesus sounded so strange.
Just hope nothing serious has happened to him.
on her pillow thoughts stand in line
laid in the soil like flower seeds
shoots and sprouts and winds around
she understands nothing at all
hours feel like days
and weeks a thousand years
came to look back
to a world of yesterday
Jesus and Josefine
homeless heartache
Jesus makes Josefine
believe in miracles
when she wavers
Jesus and Josefine
faithless time machine
the tempter's concubine
she needs miracles
and love
when she wavers
- Aw, there's such a long time until Christmas!
- There's only seven days left.
- That's a lot.
- Snatch one of dad's Christmas sausages.
- Christmas farts?
- No, Christmas sausages from Vendsyssel.
Well, Josefine.
We need to talk about something very important.
- Your birthday.
- When did it become important?
- It has always been important.
- I don't remember that.
I've been thinking,
after you've performed the nativity play, -
- to invite everyone here home
for a couple of hours. Oskar and the class.
- That's Christmas Eve. They won't come.
- You could invite Jesus along.
I'm going over to him today,
so I'll ask.
Come on, Lukas,
now we have to go to kindergarten.
I have the big meeting
with the publisher today.
Are you meeting Jesus today?
Say hi to him.
Mom? What would the world be like,
if there was no Christianity?
Whoa, that É That's a big question
so early in the morning.
One could say that if we were lucky,
we would have another religion, -
- that could help us understand
how the world fits together.
But if we were unlucky É
we would wander around in a spiritual darkness.
And believe in nothing.
I don't feel like answering that.
Come on, Jytte.
If Christianity
hadn't existed É
É Then I think
we would have been lost.
Yeah, then É then I think
the evil one would have gained power over us.
Jesus Christ is the truth.
Only through him can we find salvation.
Ñ Would you abolish Christianity?
- No, she won't.
Now we'll take the nativity play
right from the start. Come.
Jytte É
- I need to go to the toilet.
- We'll just get ready in the meantime.
- Hi, Thorsen.
- Hi, Josefine.
- You're certainly busy today, huh?
- I'll be back lightning fast.
So we'll see who comes back first.
You or me.
What do you mean?
Maybe I'll be done expanding
before I see you again.
No, you're not that fast.
I'm looking forward to celebrating the expansion
with a really good cup of coffee.
- See you,
- Yeah, we will.
Oskar, I'd like to
talk to you for a moment.
I was visited by an angel last night.
The angel told me that you and Josefine
have a friend who lives far away.
Yeah,
The angel said
that your friend is having a hard time right now.
But he has to deal with
his problems himself. That's important.
Do you understand that?
He must not be disturbed. The angel
is afraid that you will visit him.
- I understand.
- Good. Because I don't, actually.
Oskar, shall we go together?
I can't anymore.
There were wounds here and here,
What did that mean?
- It was just a dream.
- I was awake.
- You're keeping something secret from me.
- Jesus, you have to lend a hand.
We've got a huge order
all the way from Caesarea.
The Roman centurion will only use
the carpenter whose son has fingers of fire.
- What are we making?
- Crosses.
They've caught a bunch of pirates.
They're going to be hanged.
- Crosses É
- Oh well É Why not?
Come on.
(metal door slams)
So, Oskar? Do you want to work here after all,
now that I'm expanding the shop?
No, not really.
Have you seen Josefine here today?
Josefine? Nah.
I haven't seen anything of her.
- Are you sure?
- Of course. Do you think I'm lying?
- I'll just go around and check.
- Like hell you will. Out.
Get out of here, you little rascal!
Out with you!
It's wrong
to make crosses for the Romans.
They pay well. If we don't
make them, someone else will.
- Just grab hold down there.
- I just think it's wrong.
Do you think it's wrong too?
Ñ Yes.
Ñ Why?
- It is a cross, after all.
- And so what?
- I don't think you should make them.
- But why not?
No particular reason.
- What are you doing, Jesus?
- Is it because I'm going to die on the cross?
If you don't say it,
I won't bother seeing you again.
Yes, you're going to die on the cross,
but É wait!
No.
Couldn't we
get those crosses finished up?
Is that you again?
Get out!
Maybe I'd like to
work here.
Oh É That's a different tune, huh?
Then I'll get out
an employment contract.
The pay isn't anything to brag about,
but on the other hand, free food.
No!
Come here!
Come here now!
Oskar, you rascal!
You don't do that!
Oskar! You stay here!
Hi.
Didn't we have an agreement that
you wouldn't come down here?
Sorry.
What happened?
- I don't know É
- Why is Jesus upset?
He says we have to leave.
Ñ I'll talk to him.
- I'll come with.
- Is it the Romans who crucify me?
Ñ Yes.
- You mustn't tell him that.
- You have to tell me the truth.
- The crucified one in your mother's church?
- Yes, that's you.
Why are they crucifying me?
Because you're the Son of God.
Then I refuse to be the Son of God.
I want to be allowed to live.
You two stay here!
And if you follow me, then É
- What on earth have I done?
- What's happening?
- Where's Jesus?
- He ran that way.
jesus!
Take it easy.
He'll be fine again.
Maybe.
What's all this commotion?
- Jesus has run away.
- Oh.
I wouldn't have been allowed to
behave like that when I was an apprentice.
But apparently these are new times.
- See you,
- See you.
- What do we do now?
- We probably shouldn't interfere anymore.
We can only hope
that he becomes good again.
Come.
(heavy thud)
- What is that strange sound?
- No idea.
Come.
Everything here is completely changed.
We can't get out.
What's happening here?
- I don't know.
- It's completely blocked off here.
Try to look.
(metal door slams)
Who let you two slackers off?
- What are you talking about?
- Get to work!
There you are, 47.
We need your labor.
Dad!
- Why do you call me 47?
- That's your name.
My name is Josefine.
And yours is Jesper.
I'm 24.
The one who gave birth to you is 33.
You're 47, now get to work.
The one who gave birth to meÉ
What is all this?
Steam pressure is dropping!
More speed on the boilers.
See what happens
when you change history.
Jesus doesn't want to be God's son. So
the present gets remade into this.
At least I'll try
to find my family.
Then there's food.
Yuck! It tastes awful.
That's no big deal,
dad.
- Sorry, 24.
- It's food. It just has to be eaten.
- I think it tastes good.
- Eat now, 47.
We have a hard day tomorrow.
Lots of work.
You're supposed to go to the church.
You're a priest.
Priest? What's that?
Don't you know Jesus
or Christianity at all?
- Who's that?
- What about Christmas Eve?
I don't understand
what she's talking about. Christmas Eve?
Then I have my birthday
all to myself.
We don't celebrate birthdays here.
- What about God?
- We are all gods.
Some of us a little more than others.
- Who lives up there?
- The Overboss. The one who is most god-like.
Come. We have to sleep now.
We need to be fresh for tomorrow.
Dear God in Heaven. I've come to
make a real mess of everything.
I hope you'll help me
remake the world, -
- so everything becomes as before, Amen.
- Who are you talking to?
- I'm talking to God, Lukas.
My name is 58, -
- but I like it when
you call me Lukas.
That's good, Lukas,
but now you have to sleep.