Are you comfortably seated in front of the TV?
Are you ready for a real Christmas story?
There were wounds here.
Jesus has sent for Josefine.
He must speak with her.
I don't think you should make them.
- What are you doing?
- Am I to die on the cross?
Josefine admits to Jesus,
that he will die on the cross as an adult.
- Jesus becomes furious.
- Oskar, I want to talk to you.
Jytte has been visited by an angel
and warns Oskar.
The angel said,
that your friend is having a hard time right now.
- You must not visit your friend.
- He must handle his problems himself.
Oskar goes to Nazareth
to bring Josefine home.
- Jesus doesn't want to be God's son.
- I want to be allowed to live.
He wants to decide over his own life
and runs away.
When Josefine and Oskar return,
the world has changed.
Josefine's family knows nothing about
Christmas or God.
- You're number 47. Get started!
- They don't celebrate birthdays either.
The world has become like this,
because Jesus doesn't want to be God's son.
We have changed the story.
In her evening prayer, Josefine prays
for help to change the world.
on her pillow thoughts stand in line
laid in the soil like flower seeds
shoots and sprouts and winds around
she understands nothing at all
hours feel like days
and weeks a thousand years
came to look back
to a world of yesterday
Jesus and Josefine
homeless heartache
Jesus gets Josefine
to believe in miracles
when she wavers
Jesus and Josefine
faithless time machine
the tempter's concubine
she needs miracles
and love
when she wavers
Stop it now.
Of course he'll come back.
He's gone for a trip into the desert
to be alone like last time.
He simply got so angry.
Those are crosses too.
How can you make crosses for the Romans?
They're just crosses.
Of course he'll come.
- Has Jesus returned?
- Not yet.
- We don't know where he is.
- That's not good.
- No. What shall we do?
- There's nothing you can do.
What has been foretold
will not happen.
The savior who was born
denies to save.
God will abandon mankind.
From now on, they must live without hope.
Farewell, Maria and Josef.
No, wait a minute!
What shall we do?
I curse the day,
the girl from the North came here.
- If I see her again …
- It's not Josefine's fault.
Cursed be the day,
she came here!
- We've searched the whole town. He's gone.
- Just hope nothing bad has happened.
- I think he'll come back.
- Jesus won't come back.
- Why not?
- The ruler of darkness has lured him away.
Now we must wait a thousand years
for a new savior.
The time of miracles is over.
- Do you know where he is?
- I know nothing.
- We have to do something.
- What?
Search the neighboring towns.
Jesus must be somewhere.
Come on, Judas. You search east of
Nazareth. I'll take the towns to the west.
- 58, 47.
- Dad, stop it.
I've slept like the dead.
That's not so strange either.
Come on now, 47, we're busy,
You have to go to work.
- I'm supposed to go to school.
- I want to go to school too,
Schools …. that's forbidden.
Everyone works.
It's our duty as gods.
There's no spruce in the hair
in this world.
- What does that mean, 24?
- I actually don't know.
- 47 says so many strange things.
- What does it look like outside?
How would I know.
I've never been outside.
- Aren't you curious?
- Nah.
Come on out and eat your feed.
He says you know him.
We call him the boy without a number.
- Oskar, are you okay?
- Do I look like it?
Where are your parents?
I must be
in the wrong furnace room.
You won't get any of our feed.
— Shall we look for your parents?
— We'd better remake the world.
We must find the nativity play
and go back to Jesus.
Hello, you there! Aren't you going to shovel coal?
- The steam pressure is too low!
- Come on. Come on.
Come on!
- Look there.
- Look at what?
Jytte!
Come.
Jytte?
Why do you call me Jytte?
My name is 12.
- Sorry. Hi, 12.
- Come, sit down.
Sit down. There.
- What are you all doing here?
- Shh.
We have a little secret school here.
The guards mustn't know anything.
Hi, Emilie.
My name is 109, by the way.
Today we're going to hear about angels.
Angels are not welcome
here in our world.
Angels are some of the most beautiful
beings that exist.
When an angel comes flying
on its white wings, -
- then my heart fills with great joy.
- Have you seen an angel, number 12?
- Once while I was sleeping, one came.
(door slams)
It told me,
that the world can become different.
Is that true?
It also told me,
that one day a savior will be born, -
- who will give faith, hope, and love
to us humans.
We are not humans.
We are gods.
No, we are not gods,
We are humans.
(engine noise)
Overseer, quick!
Come on! Back to your work.
The overseer mustn't see you
with me.
- I want to have a talk with the overseer.
- Me too.
Down on your knees!
Show respect for the overseer!
Thorsen!
47, huh...
you came after all, huh?
Hey there.
You don't have a number at all.
That's how it goes.
You know,
we're called Oskar and Josefine.
Know what?
Not in this world.
What do you think of my extension?
Impressive, right?
- You've tricked me.
- Yeah, and know what?
Isn't it one of existence's little,
fun things, that we can trick each other?
- You're 100 percent psychopath.
- Yeah, and know what?
In this world, "psychopath"
isn't an insult.
47... thanks for the help.
And let's see about
getting some coal on that stove!
Are you crazy, 47?
You can't talk like that to the overseer.
Thorsen is a fool.
He has no right to this.
47 and the boy without a number,
get to it.
- This isn't some beach vacation.
- What's a beach vacation?
I don't know.
I don't care either.
Look, we go that way
to get into Thorsen's shop.
We run over to the nativity scene
and set it up again.
You have to work. Come on, 47
and the boy without a number.
The pressure isn't high enough yet.
No, here.
- The nativity scene is gone.
- It must be somewhere else.
(evil laughter)
You're right about that,
boy without a number.
Do you really think I'm so naive
to leave it standing out here?
Now you two come with me.
There's still a ton of coal
that needs shoveling. Come here.
Be more careful with your mischief
in the future.
Sorry, overseer.
It won't happen again.
Otherwise you'll be sent down
to the furnace cellar below.
- There's no beach vacation down there.
- We'll keep an eye on them.
You disgusting...
I wouldn't do that,
if I were you, 47.
That reminds me, we need to do
something about that in there.
Tell us more about the angels.
One day they will come down to us -
- and tell us humans
that a savior will be born.
Son of the only God.
Stop that lie story!
It will never happen. Out with you, kids!
Number 12,
you seem to need a trip to solitary.
Then there's food.
It's fine that you help out, but you
don't get any of our food.
- You can have my share of the porridge.
- You decide that yourself, 47.
But don't come tonight
begging for more to eat.
- Dad, show some kindness.
- What does kindness mean?
Don't listen to 47.
She says many words we don't know.
Like 12.
She told about the angels.
And what did she get out of it?
Now she's in the dungeon.
Hi, Judas. You look tired.
I've been all the way to Cana
to look for Jesus.
- Did you find him?
- No. Unfortunately.
Jesus?
- Have you found him?
- No, but I met a caravan.
They had seen a boy walking alone
towards the coast.
It could have been someone else.
They said he looked angry.
What is he going to the coast for now?
Jytte. Hi, Jytte.
- Sorry, number 12.
- It's nice that you call me Jytte.
It's a nice name.
The guards just mustn't hear it.
- Can we help you with something?
- No, thanks anyway.
Around here there are rarely any
who help each other.
Have you heard anything about
a magic nativity play?
- I don't know what you're talking about.
- The guard is coming.
Yes, wait a bit!
An angel once whispered in my ear
that the overseer has a magic box.
- Come on, Josefine!
- Did the angel say where it was?
I believe
he has it up with him.
- Okay. Thanks.
- Take care of yourselves.
- What are you doing here?
- They're standing and spitting on me.
Then it's okay.
Just spit away.
Stop it!
See you,
(heavy thud in the distance)
Dear God. Tomorrow you must help us
get up to Thorsen.
We just need to find the nativity play
and then travel back to Jesus.
Who is God?
- It's him who created the world.
- At least not this world.
Thorsen created that one.
But tomorrow we remake it.
Amen.