Are you comfortably seated in front of the TV?
Are you ready for a real Christmas story?
Okay.
The angel visits Joseph and Mary
and says, all hope is lost.
What has been foretold
will not happen.
The savior who was born
refuses to save.
The time of miracles is over.
Simon and Judas decide
to look for Jesus.
You search in the cities east of Nazareth,
I search to the west.
Oskar and Josefine meet Jytte,
who is not called Jytte, but number 12.
She has a secret school,
where she tells the children about angels.
- Angels are not welcome here.
- Show respect for the overbo!
Finally they meet the so-called overbo:
It is the devil himself. Thorsen.
47.
They try to sneak back to
the nativity play, but it's gone.
Stop that lie of a story!
Jytte is seized by the guards
and thrown into a dungeon.
In her evening prayer, Josefine prays to
get up to Thorsen.
They must find the nativity play,
so they can travel back to Jesus.
Tomorrow you must help us to
get up to Thorsen.
on her pillow thoughts stand in line
laid in the earth like flower seeds
shoots and sprouts and winds around
she understands nothing at all
hours feel like days
and weeks a thousand years
came to look back
to a world of yesterday
Jesus and Josefine
homeless heartache
but Jesus makes Josefine
believe in miracles
when she wavers
Jesus and Josefine
faithless time machine
tempter's concubine
she needs miracles
when she wavers
Hi, Simon. Can I tempt you with something?
- What's wrong?
- It was more fun when Jesus was here.
- I get an idea.
- What?
We write down everything
we've experienced with Jesus.
- We'll get rich.
- I'd rather have Jesus back.
Caesarea.
- Why do you say "Caesarea"?
- I see where Jesus is. In Caesarea.
What is Jesus doing in a Roman city?
He thinks he's free,
but he's captured.
- Then we must free him.
- Only one can free him. It's the girl.
The girl from the North.
Now there's food. Eat it fast,
so we can get to work.
- So the overboss doesn't get mad.
- Oh, I'm so hungry.
Come, Oskar.
Now I'll get you something to eat.
What does the boy without a number want here?
You don't belong here. Get lost!
- Do you realize he's starving?
- He's not getting any of ours.
- He's actually my friend.
- What do you need friends for, 47?
- I want a friend too.
— Shut up and eat, 58.
Sit down,
I'll tell you something.
Back when I was a little under-god,
I wished for a friend too.
- But I did better without.
- Mom, friends are important.
Come, Oskar.
(siren wails)
More coal on! More coal on!
- We have to find that nativity play now.
- But how do we get up there?
- What are you doing?
- Going to the only one who can help.
Where are you going?
- Can we spit on the prisoner?
- Then spit. And spit for me too.
Hi, Jytte.
No, how strange.
I think I've just dreamed about you.
- What did you dream?
- Imagine, I've forgotten.
How do we get up to the overboss?
Everyone who's tried has been sentenced
to life in the room machines, so watch out.
- We need to go up there.
- Have you spat anything?
(spits)
- Stop it.
- Good, that's how she should have it.
Stop it.
- Sorry, Jytte.
- It's okay.
We'd better go.
No, wait a bit.
Now I remember.
I dreamed I was visited by an angel.
And she said to me,
that I should give you this one.
- What is it?
- I don't know.
She said it can only be opened
if you really need it.
And I mean "really",
What's in it
can only be used once.
Just once.
Okay. Thanks.
(boiling and rumbling)
Now we just need to find some
9 9
way to get up there.
Yeah, but how?
47?
— You can't skip work.
- I work for the overboss.
- No, you don't.
- Yes, we do. Isn't that right?
We help him see
that everyone does their work.
I don't believe that.
Then we'll probably
have to report her.
You won't do that.
We'll say you're using
your work time to talk to us.
(siren)
Can we get the pressure up?
Get to work then.
It's your fault the pressure's dropping.
We'll never get past him.
I'll get him out of the way.
— Don't touch the landlord's property.
- The landlord is a fool!
(laughs maliciously)
Oskar?
I'll grumble at him.
(door creaks)
This is our apartment after all.
(church bells toll in the distance)
47, I've been waiting for you. Welcome.
- This is our apartment.
- Now it's mine.
Would you like some buns?
I baked them myself.
They're simply perfect.
Now watch this.
(egg timer rings)
They've had … ten minutes.
At 180 degrees, Neither a minute
too much or a minute too little.
- Would you like a cup of coffee?
- I don't drink coffee.
Then I'll just have one myself.
Why the hell
doesn't this shit work?
(gong sounds)
How many times do I have to tell you?
More coal on it!
(sirens sound in the distance)
(coffee machine sputters)
There.
Ah yes. You know what?
I've always wanted
to come up into the light.
And now I'm here. Thanks to you.
Yeah, fie on Satan.
Whoa whoa whoa ….
There is no Satan.
We don't know that word here.
- I actually think it's you.
- Yeah, you could say that.
But after you got Jesus to
give up his future as a prophet, -
- God has abandoned humanity.
And so we've all become gods,
there's no difference between good and evil, -
- and so we
don't need any Satan.
No, I … I want …
I'd much rather have you
call me grandpa.
- Then "worst-grandpa". That's up to you.
- You're not my grandpa.
No, but I can be
the whole world's grandpa.
I can be a real grandpa.
With spruce in my hair. Now watch.
(muffled explosions)
That's how the world should look.
That's the ugliest thing
I've ever seen.
I think it's unbelievably beautiful.
How glad I am
that I chose you for the task.
- Why did you choose me?
- Jesus saw right through me.
A young, pretty December girl like you,
who thinks a bit too much about herself.
That's what it took to get Jesus to
give up the idea of being God's son.
Yes, love makes you blind,
as they say.
But I can comfort you with the fact that
he had a long and good life.
Did he?
You know what?
I have something I want to show you.
Now just listen.
This one is simply so exciting.
It's the history of the Roman Empire.
Are you listening?
You talked about
how Jesus had a long life.
Ow!
- Welcome, boy without a number.
- Then you can sit and think about it.
She'll manage.
- Has she gotten up there?
- I think so.
(sighs)
There's one thing about the superintendent.
He's too good to tempt.
Yes, thanks. He hasn't done anything else
in the month of December.
I hope she's strong.
Otherwise, all hope is lost.
(Thorsen hums)
Yes, here it is.
"The famous gladiator,
Jesus of Nazareth, -
- celebrated the triumph of his life in Rome,
where he defeated Barabbas.
It was that fight that gave Jesus
the nickname 'king of the gladiators'.
Afterwards, Jesus retired,
had nine children and a happy old age."
Try looking.
Here you can just see,
Yes, shouldn't we then
let Jesus rest in peace?
- No!
- Goodbye, Thorsen.
Now stop that.
Jesus has chosen his future.
He can still choose it again.
Do you really want him to hang
there on the cross like a Christmas elf?
Do you realize how much it hurts -
- to have nails hammered through
both hands and both feet?
Do you really want to subject
the poor guy to that?
Do him the service
of letting him grow old and happy.
Listen now. There's something
I have to show you.
I can do more for
you and your family, -
- than you ever dream of.
No, Lukas. It's Josephine's turn.
- Thanks.
- Doesn't it look cozy?
Then there are buns.
It's Josephine's favorite recipe.
That's how you can have it if you stay.
- Now we just need grandpa.
- Hi, grandpa.
Hi, everyone. I have gifts with me,
- No, that just won't do.
- For all of you.
Is it because I'm here?
You can have it the way you want it.
I can disappear.
I can move down to my old shop,
if that's what you want.
Now look.
Look, Oskar is with us.
- Today is Josephine's birthday.
- Christmas is canceled.
Now you have your birthday to yourself.
Isn't that what you've wished for?
Hooray, hooray, hooray!
- And then the long one.
- Hoorayyy!
Wasn't it about time then -
- to get that finger away?
You can become powerful.
You can become over-gods.
You can get all the under-gods
to slave for you.
Could you imagine that?
In reality, you're just like me.
Like this.
(laughs)
(sighs with relief)
Unfortunately, Thorsen.
No! No!
No, no!
- Get away from us.
- Don't.
- She is Satan's emissary!
- Of course not.
- I was Satan's emissary.
- And what are you now?
- I'm here to get Jesus back.
- Why should I trust you?
- Because you have to.
- Josefine, good you came.
Joshua said that only
the girl from the North can save Jesus.
- Where is he?
- In Caesarea. We can be there tomorrow.
- I'm coming along.
- No, Maria.
Wait here, I'll pack
some bread for you.
I have to remember this one.
Boy without number, wake up.
I dreamed,
that 47 is on the way to the Savior.
Will you pray with me?
Dear angel who protects us.
Let 47 arrive safely, -
- and let the power of evil be broken.
Amen.