Are you comfortably seated in front of the TV?
Are you ready for a real Christmas story?
Okay.
Simon and Judas get a tip from Joshua.
Jesus is in the Roman city of Caesarea.
He thinks he's free,
but he's captured.
- Then we must free him.
- Only one can free Jesus.
But there's only one who can help.
The girl from the North.
- May we spit on the prisoner?
- Then spit. And spit for me too.
Josefine and Oskar visit Jytte.
She gives Josefine a package,
that she got from an angel.
It can only be opened,
when she is really in need.
And I mean "really",
— Don't touch the overseer's property.
- The overseer is a fool!
Oskar sacrifices himself and lets himself be captured,
so Josefine can get up to Thorsen.
She enters her old apartment,
which Thorsen has taken over.
I had expected
you to have come a bit earlier.
He thanks her,
because she got Jesus to give up.
You have changed the world.
Josefine finds the nativity scene game.
Thorsen tempts.
I can do more for you and your family
than you ever dream of.
But Josefine doesn't let herself be tempted.
No!
Together with Simon and Judas
she goes out to find Jesus.
- I'll pack some bread for you.
- I'll remember this one.
on her pillow thoughts stand in line
laid in the ground like flower seeds
shoots and sprouts and winds around
she understands nothing at all
hours feel like days
and weeks a thousand years
came to look back
to a world of yesterday
Jesus and Josefine
homeless heartache
but Jesus gets Josefine
to believe in miracles
when she wavers
Jesus and Josefine
faithless time machine
the tempter's concubine
she needs miracles
when she wavers
(muffled explosions)
Psst!
- Good morning.
- Did you sleep well?
Boy without a number, have you seen 47?
We can't understand where she is.
She has to show up at work soon,
otherwise the overseer will go mad.
- She's left.
- You can't leave from here.
She's gone away
to make the world better.
There is no better world.
She's at least
gone down to clean up.
- Now she's gotten herself into something.
- Yeah, she baked a cake in it.
Did she bake a cake?
Only the high priest is allowed to bake cake.
If the angel is with her,
she can overthrow the high priest.
Watch what you say.
Think if he hears you.
We haven't heard anything at least.
Come here, 58.
I have something for you.
Thanks,
- I can't go on anymore.
- Come on, Judas. We're almost there.
- I have blisters all over.
- You can walk even if you have blisters.
Why should she decide?
Remember what the old one said.
Only the girl from the North can free Jesus.
- That's surely nonsense.
- Now you stop.
Stop now. Then we'll sit down
and take a break and eat breakfast.
Judas, give us the loaves right away.
- Uh …
- Uh what, Judas? Have you lost them?
- Then you have to get some.
- Can you see any bakery?
- That's not funny.
- You don't need to scold me.
I'm not scolding.
- Stop and come see.
- See what?
Caesarea. It's right there.
Fantastic.
(gladiator clears his throat)
(growls)
(Jesus roars)
That's what happens when little boys
want to play with the big ones.
- Welcome to the gladiator school.
- Thanks, Pardos.
- I hoped we wouldn't meet.
- I want to be the king of the gladiators.
You've bound yourself to
a slave contract.
- Are you aware of that?
- Yes.
You risk being
beaten to death halfway.
- One would think you had run away.
- I have too.
I won't interfere in that.
As long as you understand, -
- that this is your life from now on.
Yes,
I expect
you're ready to sacrifice everything.
And you're ready to
hail the emperor of Rome.
Now I could slap you,
because you don't answer.
Do you know why I don't?
- You have a huge talent.
- Thanks.
Probably the biggest I've seen.
Now I was gentle with you.
Later we'll get to it.
You'll probably break an arm or a leg.
That's what it is to be a gladiator.
Jesus ….
- What are you doing here?
- We've come to save you.
- I don't want to be saved.
- You have to come with us.
The only thing I have to do is do
what's in the contract.
- I have to be here for ten years.
- You're not quite smart.
- You can't sign that.
- Do you get a lot of money?
- No, but I'll become famous.
- You're not going to be a gladiator.
Jesus, who are you chattering with?
Get ready for the fight.
- We'll pick you up tonight.
- No, you won't. Goodbye.
Now I'm looking forward to the transformation.
Will it come like a whisper of angels,
that hover across the sky?
Or do you think it comes
quietly and calmly, while we sleep?
- It might be that nothing happens.
- You don't think so? I hope so.
Now I think we're going to be set free.
I think that's the transformation.
Sit down. You're coming with.
Stand straight and receive your judgment,
boy without a number.
Listen to the overseer's words:
The right of the strongest sentences
the sub-subgod without number -
- to eternal forced labor
in the iron machines.
- Accept the judgment or die.
- Do you accept the judgment?
Do you accept the judgment? Come with.
Row then. You have to make the bulb light up.
And you keep rowing.
Otherwise you'll get the whip.
I'm keeping an eye on you.
(gong sounds)
So there's good news
for all gods.
The pressure is fine and stable, -
- so just keep scratching.
Then you'll get strength and freedom.
(sticks out tongue)
There.
(Josef hammers)
(Thorsen clears his throat)
Excuse me, is there something
we can help with?
I'm looking for a boy.
A very special boy.
Yes, we are too. That is,
his friends are out looking for him.
Is there among his friends
a strange girl?
Yes,
That's the one I've come
to warn him against.
Well, then you've come too late.
She's been here.
She's not to be trusted.
She fooled me.
That was just what I said. I said,
we shouldn't trust her.
Excuse me, who are you anyway?
I'm the one who came
to get revenge.
I've come
to collect my debt.
- My son doesn't owe you anything, does he?
- No no.
But she does.
- Do you know where they are?
— Yes.
They talked about Caesarea,
a Roman city down by the coast.
God bless you.
(thunderclap)
Thank you, ma'am.
Shut your mouth then.
(panting)
- There.
- That's fine, Judas.
- How do we get Jesus home?
- I think we should kidnap him.
No, that won't work.
Jesus has to come of his own free will.
Otherwise, he'll just run away again.
What about saying,
I've been bitten by a snake?
Then Jesus will have to
come to save my life.
- Bad idea, Judas.
- No, it's not a bad idea.
We'll make Jesus believe
he has healed Judas.
Jesus regains his faith, and then
maybe he'll realize who he is.
- Let's give it a chance.
- Come on.
Jesus?
Shall we fight?
- There are two who want to talk to you.
- Who are they?
Your friends say you have a sick
comrade lying out in the desert.
He asks for your help.
- Is it Judas?
- He has been bitten by a snake.
- Maybe he'll die.
- I'm not going to heal him. It's over.
- He just wants to say hi to you.
- Before he dies.
I have to fight.
Visit your friend. If you heal him,
it'll make you a better gladiator.
God be with you.
Who are you?
- I don't know if you dare to hear it.
- I dare to hear anything.
I am the Lord,
who created Heaven and Earth.
Are you God?
Are you hungry?
There.
You have to do me a favor.
I have decided
that Jesus shall not save the world.
He shall be a gladiator.
That's the best for him.
We all have to do what's
best for us. Do we agree?
Yes, if you say so.
You just make sure
he gets back to Caesarea.
Then I'll teach you
a little baking trick or two someday.
Judas?
Farewell, my friend.
Where were you bitten?
You were bitten just now.
- He doesn't look very sick.
- Yeah, he's about to die.
- Is that true?
- Nah, I'm perfectly fine.
Then why do they say
you've been bitten?
- I don't know.
- Judas.
- This is the second time you've lied to me.
- Sorry, but just hear me out.
- Are you going to fool me some more?
- I just came from the future.
Oskar has been taken prisoner,
and my parents have become slaves.
- Satan rules the world.
- Why should I care about that?
The future was changed because of you,
because you don't want to be God's son.
- I want to be a gladiator.
- Jesus is right.
If he wants to be a gladiator,
then let him be a gladiator.
Thanks, Judas.
You're the only one who understands me.
Shall we tie him up?
Just let him go.
Dear God, hear my prayer.
If I can't get Jesus
to understand, can't you?
But God wants
Jesus to be a gladiator.
How do you know?
I just know.
God, you are the only one
who can help Jesus. Amen.