Are you comfortably seated in front of the TV?
Are you ready for a real Christmas story?
Okay.
After having walked all night —
- when Josefine, Simon and Judas
arrive at the Roman city of Caesarea.
Jesus has started at gladiator school,
where he is trained by Pardos.
(Jesus roars)
Jesus is not
interested in coming along.
- What are you doing here?
- We're here to save you.
I don't want to be saved.
Thorsen goes down to Nazareth
to stop Josefine.
Your friends have
a very sick friend out in the desert.
Josefine and Simon trick Jesus into believing
that Judas has been bitten by a snake.
I won't heal him.
Pardos tells Jesus
that he must help his friend.
Meanwhile, Judas gets a visit from Thorsen.
- Who are you?
- He claims to be God.
He doesn't look particularly sick.
- He's about to die.
- I'm perfectly fine.
Judas reveals
that the snakebite is a lie.
This is the second time you've lied to me.
Jesus gets mad
and goes back to gladiator school.
In her evening prayer, Josefine asks God
to intervene directly.
Because God is the only one
who can make Jesus understand.
Dear God, hear my prayer.
on her pillow thoughts stand in line
laid in the soil like flower seeds
shoot up and sprout and twist around
she understands nothing at all
hours feel like days
and weeks a thousand years
came to look back
to a world of yesterday
Jesus and Josefine
homeless heartache
but Jesus makes Josefine
believe in miracles
when she wavers
Jesus and Josefine
faithless time machine
tempter's concubine
she needs miracles
when she wavers
Wake up, Simon.
- Simon.
- What?
We're going to have to
talk to Jesus again.
- But he won't.
- You want him back too.
Yeah yeah, but … We'll try once more.
First we need something to eat.
Good idea, except
we don't have any bread.
- Where did you get them from?
- I got them from God, actually.
Well, God just stopped by
and took some bread with him?
He was actually sitting right here
and baked them from two stones.
- What did he say then?
- That Jesus is going to be a gladiator.
- You're lying.
- Why do you never believe me?
- You can't be trusted.
- You don't trust God either?
- Yes, I do.
- Then let's leave Jesus alone.
- But I promised Josefine …
- God will be furious.
- I'm going home now.
- I'll come with you.
- Simon, you promised.
- I trust God more than you.
(Pardo groans)
Can you lie down now, boy!
- I'll never lie down!
- Then take this!
(panting and groaning)
- I'll get you down.
- I just need to sit for a bit.
There, I got you after all.
I'll be back in a bit.
(it boils and rumbles)
Where am I?
Hi, don't you remember me?
I'm Josefine's friend, Jesus.
- 58, hurry up, you're behind.
- My arms are tired.
You have to, otherwise we won't get food.
You can't tell me how to get to
gladiator school, right?
(Jytte sobs)
Why did you say there were angels
when it's not true?
- I'll never do it again.
- We don't believe in angels.
There are angels.
What is this place?
(groans)
- You know that bulb has to light up.
- I can't do more.
- Oskar?
- Should I swing the whip?
Oskar!
Do you really think
he can hear what you're saying?
Who are you?
I am nothing.
Because the one I was supposed to be,
I'll never become.
- Why not?
- Why do you ask so stupidly?
I am you as an adult. I am Jesus.
The Jesus who is the Son of God.
But I will never
get to exist.
Are you me?
You held the whole world in your hand.
But look what happens,
This is what the world looks like,
just because you want to be a gladiator.
I don't want to die on a cross.
And so people have to live and die
without hope of salvation in such a world?
Can you feel good, little Jesus?
Sometimes one must sacrifice oneself.
What should I do?
You know the answer.
(Oskar groans)
Are you sitting there sleeping?
Go over and get some water and fight!
And let's pick up the pace.
This time I'll smash you.
- I have to go.
- That's impossible according to your contract.
- I have to.
- Is it too hard for you?
I didn't think you were a weakling.
Did you come to make a fool of me?
I think I understand.
You could have become the greatest.
You could have shut down the Colosseum.
And gotten laurel wreaths.
Thanks for the fight.
Farewell, master,
- Aren't we going to eat?
- You only think about food.
I need something in my gut.
We're short 24 crosses.
I'm staying here lying down,
until Jesus comes back.
- You can't just lie there.
- I can assure you I can.
- There's washing and baking and …
— Not until I say so!
(knocking)
Thanks, God.
Happy days in Nazareth.
Jesus is on his way back.
Is that true?
But the road will be long, -
- and there are snakes in the desert.
Simon and Judas, wait a minute.
- Judas, I want to ask you something.
— Yes?
- What did God look like?
- He looked nice.
- Was he very big down there?
- Of course God is big.
Did he have such a deep voice?
Yes,
And he said,
Jesus should be a gladiator?
Then it might not have been God.
Who would it be then?
Satan.
Satan wouldn't dare impersonate God, would he?
Satan dares quite a lot.
But luckily I have this one.
What is it?
I don't know, but it helps.
Are you coming?
I don't think I dare,
if it has anything to do with Satan.
Fine. Then I'll do it myself.
Okay. Good luck.
Judas …
Josephine!
- Josephine?
- She sends her regards.
- Who are you?
- A merchant. My name is Natas.
- Where did Josephine go?
- She's gone home.
- Sit down, my friend.
- No, I want to catch up with her.
- I can help you.
- No thanks.
Yes, I have some bread.
And it's a long way to Nazareth.
Man does not live by
bread alone, Natas. Farewell.
Jesus, watch out for that guy!
I know who it is. Satan.
Yes, there you see, Josefine.
I really needed your help.
He saw through me right away.
(laughs maliciously)
There's nothing left
but to congratulate you two on the victory.
I'm an old sportsman.
Congratulations.
Get away! Come here!
- Josefine.
- Screw being with her.
Josefine?
- Like that!
- What happened?
- I've lost the package.
- This one?
Come on, Judas!
- Jesus!
- How strong are you then?
Will you get up again,
if your body is crushed?
How strong are you, Jesus of Nazareth?
Well, it'll be exciting to see,
if your father has really forsaken you.
- But you didn't want any help.
- Stop!
I thought
we were done with each other.
(thunderclap)
- A feather?
- Are you threatening me with a feather?
Yes!
(Thorsen laughs)
(thunderclap)
(Thorsen screams)
Now he's gone.
Farewell, Thorsen, you maggot.
(snake hisses)
Thanks for using my feather.
Your prayer was heard, Josefine.
Jesus, I think there's someone
waiting for you at home.
Just hope nothing has happened.
Something has happened,
but now it's over.
He's not dead, is he?
He's on his way.
On his way to Nazareth.
We'll continue tomorrow.
- But I thought it was God, after all.
- Judas, you are forgiven.
- Think, that one can't tell the difference.
- You can't tell the difference.
- You believed in it too.
- I hadn't seen him, after all.
You've tasted his bread, haven't you?
What's wrong?
If it weren't for him,
I never would have met you.
If it weren't for you, I wouldn't have
understood who I need to look after.
- Shall I teach you a prayer?
— Yes.
- Our Father, who art in heaven.
- I know that one well.
Hallowed be thy name,
thy kingdom come.
Thy will be done in heaven,
as it is on earth.
Give us this day our daily bread, -
- and forgive us our debts,
as we also forgive our debtors.
And lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil.
For thine is the kingdom, the power and the glory
forever. Amen.
Ugh, I mean.
If you keep
talking so loud, I can't sleep.