Are you comfortably seated in front of the TV?
Are you ready for a real Christmas story?
- You want him back too, right?
- Josefine has pitched camp in the desert.
She and Simon and Judas
want to get Jesus out of gladiator school.
- But Judas doesn't want to anymore.
- I'm going home now.
- I'll come with you.
- Simon, you promised.
He leaves the camp, and Simon goes with him.
After a hard training session with Pardos
Jesus has a strange vision.
He enters Thorsen's fireworks cellar
and sees how the world has changed.
- Who are you?
- And then he meets himself as an adult.
I am nothing. For the one
I was supposed to be, I will never become.
Jesus realizes that he must be
the savior of mankind.
See what happens.
- I have to go.
- Sit in the cell and cool off a bit.
He leaves
Pardos and the gladiator school.
- I think I get it.
- But Thorsen captures Jesus.
How strong are you, Jesus of Nazareth?
- He wants to throw him off a cliff.
- Stop!
- Are you threatening me with a feather?
- … an angel feather.
Farewell, you mealworm.
on her pillow thoughts stand in line
laid in the ground like flower seeds
shoots and sprouts and twines around
she understands nothing at all
hours feel like days
and weeks a thousand years
came to look back
to a world of yesterday
Jesus and Josefine
homeless heartache
but Jesus gets Josefine
to believe in miracles
when she wavers
Jesus and Josefine
faithless time machine
the tempter's concubine
she needs miracles
when she wavers
Good morning, Nazareth. Here we come.
My mom and dad
will be happy to see me.
I'll get such a big hug.
- Just say you've saved the world.
- Then I'll get an even bigger one.
— Just say goodbye.
— Do you want to be alone with her?
Do as I say now.
- Thanks for the ride, Josefine.
- Likewise. And thanks for the help.
- Goodbye, Josefine.
- Behave yourself now.
- What do you mean?
- I won't get involved in that.
I will write down what we've experienced,
and sell it at the markets.
- That sounds like a bad idea.
- We'll mention the girl from the North.
What is meant to be remembered
will be remembered.
And that which is to be forgotten,
will be forgotten.
Welcome, Jesus. And sorry.
Sorry for what?
I went around looking for you,
but now I know I was looking too early.
You should be allowed to
grow up in peace.
But, Jesus …
- What does he mean by that?
- That you should forget everything.
- But we can become stonrich.
- Forget it, Judas. Come on.
Okay.
Come.
Joseph?
- Oh, are you there?
— Yes.
That was good.
Jesus?
Jesus! Oh, welcome, my boy.
My boy.
I've also been running around in the desert.
Are you hungry?
- Your mother has been so worried.
- Yes, I was worried.
I didn't know what to do.
My treasure.
Then I also want to say goodbye.
Won't you eat with us?
- I have to go home.
- Are you really leaving?
Yes, my family has decided,
that we're moving on now.
You should at least have something
to strengthen you with before you leave.
Come. Sit down here,
It tastes absolutely fantastic.
It's just the food
that God has given me the skill to make.
- May I have another portion?
- You haven't been out in the desert.
That's why one can still be hungry.
Jesus' father only thinks about food.
Did you say "Jesus' father"?
I didn't notice that.
You actually said it.
You should just call me Joseph.
I know I'm not your father.
- But I want to call you father.
- Is that true?
Then I just have two fathers.
In return, I've thought about something.
Your mother is right.
You are something special. You should study.
You don't need to run around
patching wood together for me.
- But I want to be a carpenter.
- No, but you are the chosen one.
It will be a long time before he's called.
The beggar said it himself.
Jesus should be allowed to grow up first.
That suits me fine.
We have some big tasks right now.
We just shouldn't make crosses.
That otherwise pays well.
- We shouldn't make crosses for the Romans.
- I agree.
- They'll get furious.
- I'll find an excuse.
You don't need to, boy.
Dad will take care of it.
(laughs)
Josefine?
I'm sorry,
that I've been so harsh with you.
- I hope you can forgive me.
- Of course.
You're always welcome another time.
And if you need
some woodwork, I'm there.
- Yes, and my son here.
— Thanks.
- What is it?
- Just gifts. Also from my dad and mom.
- No, thanks a lot.
- You can open them on your birthday.
- How nice of you.
- It was the least we could do.
I must be on my way.
Take good care of yourself, my girl.
Safe journey.
- Can I just say goodbye?
- We'd like to join in too.
- No, Maria. Come on.
- You have to wave too.
Come on.
Well,
ah
- I could otherwise …
I would otherwise
like to come along.
- You'd better not.
- I want to see if your family is okay.
- I hope they are.
- Are you scared?
When you're done saying goodbye,
will you come and help?
Yes, Dad.
- I'll miss you too.
- We can still think of each other.
Absolutely.
So say hi to
Oskar and Lukas and your dad and mom.
I will.
Trust in God.
- Why do you say that?
- I just couldn't help it.
Is something wrong?
Just trust in God.
You'd better take this too.
(cars honk outside on the street)
(doorbell rings)
- Merry Christmas.
— Yes, thanks. Same to you.
Merry Christmas.
(goats bleat)
- Hi, Josefine.
- Good to see you.
- Congratulations! You did it.
- It would never have succeeded without you.
- I think you took a long time too.
- It's easy to change the world, right.
Do you realize,
I was in that space machine for several days?
- How did the world become normal again?
- I woke up this morning.
- Then everything was as usual.
- Cool.
But there was goat shit at the goats',
so I need to get new straw.
- What did people say about it?
- No one remembers anything.
- Except for us two.
- How strange.
We're not in the Bible anymore either.
I can't find
a word about you and me or Lukas.
I'll miss the
girl from the North.
- You're not going back down there, right?
— No no.
Shouldn't we destroy the nativity play?
No, not right now,
but I promise to do it soon.
Why not right now?
I want to look at it one last time,
and burn it
and then it goes in the wood stove.
Then you really have to promise.
Oskar, wait a minute.
- I'd like to ask you about…
- What?
No, nothing.
Is it okay if I come
and pick up the nativity play a little later?
Yes yes.
Oskar?
Is it also okay if I change clothes
before I go home?
- See you,
- See you.
Hi, Lukas.
— Hi, dad.
- Hi, sweetie.
- Hi, mom.
- Hi. Lovely.
How glad I am
to see you all together again.
We're also glad to see you.
- You arrive just in time for dinner.
- Uhm, rice pudding.
There simply
wasn't any other food in the house.
The last few days have just flown by.
I think that's wonderful. Pine needles in your hair.
Pine needles in your hair? You're getting the hang of it.
- Weren't we going to have Nazareth juice?
- What is Nazareth juice?
We always drink Nisse's nisse beer.
- And why is your head so black?
- I've been rehearsing the nativity play.
I don't know any nativity play
that gets rehearsed this much.
It was because we tried to write
the girl from the North into the play.
Who is she? There's no
"girl from the North" in the Bible.
- Have you heard of her?
- The girl from the North?
- No.
- The girl from the North is my big sister.
- Oh, gosh.
- She taught Jesus to walk on water.
You really have
a lively imagination today.
(door creaks)
(glockenspiel starts)
Hey, stop that!
Hands off.
- I was down with Jesus.
- Yeah yeah, you were.
He was sitting with his elf hat
and eating rice pudding.
You don't say anything
to dad and mom about this.
- Is that understood?
- Okay.
(owl hoots)
Dear God, thank you,
because it's a normal Christmas again.
And sorry because I
haven't destroyed the nativity play.
I hope Oskar can forgive me,
because he's actually pretty sweet.
- Who's the cutest? Jesus or Oskar?
- Lukas, be quiet!
- Josefine is in love.
- Lukas!
I still hope
Oskar thinks I'm sweet. Amen.