Are you comfortably seated in front of the TV?
Are you ready for a real Christmas story?
Okay.
After the showdown with Thorsen in the desert
Jesus and Josefine arrive -
- along with Simon and Judas
early in the morning in Nazareth.
They say goodbye to Simon and Judas.
- Thanks for the ride.
- Same to you. And thanks for the help.
- Farewell, Josefine.
- Behave yourself now.
- What do you mean?
- That's none of my business.
Mary and Joseph embrace Jesus,
as he returns.
Jesus says he's looking forward
to being a carpenter's apprentice.
You are the chosen one, after all.
It'll be a long time before you're called.
That's what the beggar said.
- Jesus should be allowed to grow up.
- Josefine says goodbye to Jesus.
And travels back to the present.
The world is normal again,
- Merry Christmas.
- Same to you.
Josefine hurries over to Oskar.
- Hi, Josefine.
- Good to see you.
Congratulations! You did it.
- Then Josefine goes home.
- You arrive just in time for dinner.
Uhm, rice pudding.
- Weren't we supposed to have Nazareth juice?
- What is Nazareth juice?
But outside the window —
- Thorsen is keeping an eye on the house.
on her pillow thoughts line up
planted in the ground like flower seeds
shoots and sprouts and winds around
she understands nothing at all
hours feel like days
and weeks a thousand years
came to look back
to a world of yesterday
Jesus and Josefine
homeless heartache
but Jesus makes Josefine
believe in miracles
when she wavers
Jesus and Josefine
faithless time machine
the tempter's concubine
she needs miracles
when she wavers
Dad, the calendar candle
has only burned down to the 18th.
We've apparently been so busy
that we've forgotten it.
And I've forgotten my calendar gift.
- Why did you throw out the baking bible?
- No one wanted to publish it.
- Of course there's that.
- Look here. Do you know what this is?
- Rejection after rejection.
- Have you dropped your cookbook?
Yes, but it's totally okay.
It's nicer to bake for you all
than to go and write a stupid book.
I'll keep it then.
Josefine, we're going to have to
talk about your birthday.
We had agreed to throw a party for you,
after you had performed the nativity play.
We can't manage to arrange it.
We're going to have to
postpone it to next year.
- That's okay.
- Just listen for a moment.
Next year we'll throw
a mega birthday party for you.
Dad, it's more important
to celebrate Christmas than my birthday.
- How sweet you are.
- Josefine, pine needle in your hair.
- By the way, I've washed your costume.
— Thanks.
(rustling)
- Hi, Oskar.
- Hi, Josefine.
- Is everything okay?
- Yeah, it just needs a wash.
Then it's good that you're cleaning it.
What about you? Are you okay?
- What do you mean?
- Nothing.
Oskar, I'm really glad that
we two managed to make the world normal again.
- Without you, then …
- Without me, what then?
Nothing.
Do you remember when you asked
if we should be boyfriend and girlfriend?
Yes,
— I was thinking that …
- I'm glad that we're friends.
Me too.
Come on, we need to go over and rehearse in the church.
(sighs)
Yes, but then I'll say thanks for today.
I think it'll be
a really nice performance.
And remember, see you tomorrow.
(faint mumbling)
- Oskar and Josefine, can you stay a bit?
- What for?
Now we'll just wait
until the others have left.
I just wanted to say thanks.
- Thanks for what?
- For the flat package with the feather in it.
- Did I give you the flat package?
- Yes, don't you remember?
I couldn't understand either
where it had gone.
I got it once
from an angel in a dream.
The next morning it was really there.
Oskar, can you come up here quick?
- Oskar, see you later,
- Yes, of course.
"See you later,"
I think you should rehearse
the last scene alone.
It can be better. It's about
getting into the heart of Joseph.
And into the heart of Mary.
And you can do that best alone.
I just need to go up and get something,
you can just start.
Come on, Josefine.
Jytte?
- Who are you?
- I'm a nightmare.
Why are you upset?
Maybe I don't want
us to just be friends.
Why not?
Because I might be in love.
Are you still in love with Jesus?
No, Oskar.
Maybe I'm in love with …
Ha!
- What was that?
- No idea.
Jytte?
- I'm damn tired of that name.
- Thorsen!
Hi there. It's almost nice
to see you again.
— A bit like the old days.
- What do you want? This is a church.
- Not a place for you.
- And why not?
It's your fault.
Up there hangs your good friend.
Come.
(laughs)
- Shall I close the doors?
- Get lost, Thorsen!
Let's leave it. You've lost anyway.
Yes, you're right, Oskar. I've lost.
But I don't want to leave
without taking you two with me!
That pleasure
I won't be cheated out of!
Shall I open the doors for you?
(explosion)
Now you two are going down to
the deepest coal cellar.
There you can shovel coal
the rest of your lives.
(Thorsen laughs maliciously)
Help!
Hold on!
You can do nothing!
My power is greater than yours.
- We must trust in God.
- Trust in God?
Yes, just like Jesus said.
Our Father, who art in heaven.
Hallowed be thy name, thy kingdom come.
Thy will be done on earth
as it is in heaven.
Stop that!
Give us this day our daily bread
and forgive us our trespasses.
And lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil.
Stop it now!
For thine is the kingdom, the power and the glory
forever. Amen!
(Thorsen screams)
(doors slam)
Are you okay?
What about Jytte?
(banging sounds)
Let me out. Let me …
Hi there.
I must have stumbled into the closet
somehow.
Have you practiced your scene?
Yes. We've gotten good at it.
Right, Oskar?
Yes,
- We accidentally knocked over a set piece.
- We have to put it up before we leave.
(sighs)
(Jytte shudders)
Yes. Now I think it's nice here again.
(the door opens)
Hi!
Hi, Lukas.
- Hi, Lukas.
- Hi, Louise.
How nice it is.
And everything is ready for tomorrow?
- Yes, more or less.
- We hope so.
There's nothing wrong, right?
No.
That's good. A fuse could have
blown or something.
Lukas, wouldn't you like
to be in our nativity play?
- As what?
- Then you'd play baby Jesus.
- In Egypt. Instead of the doll.
- I'd like that. Jesus is my friend.
That sounds fun, huh?
Josefine, do you want to come now?
There's something
I need to ask. Come, Lukas.
- Well, thanks for the help.
- Likewise.
I'm glad that we're friends,
Me too.
Do you remember what you promised yesterday?
About the nativity play? It's ruined.
Okay. That's good.
- Dad, I'm going to play Jesus.
- How nice.
- What is my nativity play doing there?
- You're not supposed to know that at all.
- What did you use it for?
- Oh, it was supposed to be a surprise.
- Wow, how nice.
- Can you eat it?
- Not until the day after tomorrow.
- Shall we go down to Jesus?
You're not going anywhere
until you've set the table.
Sorry if I took something I wasn't supposed to.
I just needed
a model for my cake nativity play.
Just ask next time.
It's quite special
that it lights up when you touch the manger.
- Is there a secret bulb somewhere?
- Yes, down in the manger.
Why is there no baby Jesus
in the manger? There is in my cake house.
My Jesus is gone. That's just how it is.
Thanks for the loan.
Dear God in Heaven.
I'm glad we managed to send
Thorsen down to the bottom boiler room.
I'm also glad
that we're friends again, -
- even though I'd rather
have been boyfriend and girlfriend.
- Why are you whispering?
- That's none of your business.
- Those who whisper, lie.
- That's not true.
But if we can't be boyfriend and girlfriend,
then it's okay, we're friends, Amen.