Are you comfortably seated in front of the TV?
Are you ready for a real Christmas story?
Okay.
Josefine is back in the present.
The world has become normal again.
Dad, the Advent candle
has only burned down to the 18th.
We've apparently been so busy,
that we've forgotten to light it.
In the family, Jesper and Louise
are behind with all the Christmas preparations.
Josefine, we're going to have to
talk about your birthday.
- What's wrong with it?
- We can't manage to arrange it.
Josefine meets with Oskar.
She wants to say that she's in love.
Do you remember when you asked,
if we should be boyfriend and girlfriend?
— I was thinking that …
- I'm glad we're just friends.
In the church, Jytte thinks
that they should rehearse the final scene alone.
Suddenly Thorsen appears.
No!
We must trust in God.
They succeed in chasing Thorsen away
by trusting in God -
- and praying the Lord's Prayer.
Do you remember what you promised yesterday?
Oskar asks if she has
ruined the nativity play.
Josefine says that she has.
Even though it's not true.
In her evening prayer, Josefine says,
that she wants to be friends with Oskar.
But most of all she wants to be girlfriend,
If we can't be boyfriend and girlfriend,
it's okay that we're friends. Amen.
on her pillow thoughts stand in line
laid in the soil like flower seeds
shoots and sprouts and winds around
she understands nothing at all
hours feel like days
and weeks a thousand years
came to look back
to a world of yesterday
Jesus and Josefine
homeless heartache
but Jesus gets Josefine
to believe in miracles
when she wavers
Jesus and Josefine
faithless time machine
the tempter's concubine
she needs miracles
when she wavers
Today is Josefine's birthday,
hurrah, hurrah, hurrah.
She surely gets a gift,
that she has wished for this year.
With delicious chocolate and cakes too.
Happy birthday, sweetie.
— Here, it's for you.
— Thanks.
You can't guess what it is.
- No, it's an elf hat.
- I told you so.
- Is that how it's supposed to sit?
— Yes.
And do you know what the best
thing about your birthday is?
It's that it's Christmas Eve.
(laughs)
Happy birthday, sweetie.
12 years old. I must say.
Do you know what's the best
about your birthday?
It's that it's your birthday.
A little pre-gift.
You'll get the rest later.
I hope you like it.
Wow, it's so cool.
— Happy birthday, sweet darling.
- Thanks, dad.
How nice it is.
You have to excuse me.
I'm completely Christmas-stressed.
- But I made these myself,
- Then I'll take the biggest one.
On my birthday
I want the biggest one.
Chocolate ball?
Oh, sorry. Yes, thanks.
I'm sitting thinking about
my Christmas sermon.
I don't think it's good enough.
Yes yes, it'll be fine.
- Mom, is something wrong with you?
- No, of course not.
I just don't know
what to say in church.
What I have is completely miserable.
Actually, I'd like to
talk to Jesus. Your friend Jesus.
Last time he said something
that I could really use.
I just think he'd say,
you should trust in God.
Trust in God? Yeah.
No, I don't think
that's enough for a whole Christmas sermon.
I don't think so.
Okay, I have to go to Oskar.
See you in church.
And don't be late.
You're in the Nativity play.
Hi, Oskar.
- Hi, Emilie.
- Hi, Josefine.
See you in church, Oskar.
- Should Emilie play Mary instead?
- Me and Emilie are just good friends.
- Just like us two.
- That's what we'll say.
— Happy birthday.
— Thanks.
I haven't bought a gift for you.
The last days have been quite busy.
That's okay. That the world became normal,
is the best birthday gift.
Do you have your role down?
- I hope so.
- Come on.
(church bells ring)
So, now you just watch, Jesus.
You hold here,
and then you hold the board.
No, not there,
you'll saw your finger.
- Has he cut himself?
- No no, I'm watching him.
- If he gets even a little cut …
- No, calm down. I … Ouch!
See what happened now.
- You come yelling and screaming too.
- Let me see where you cut yourself.
There is no wound.
Jesus, that's a miracle.
Rise up, Joseph of Abraham's lineage.
Take the child and its mother with you
back to the land of Israel.
For the one who wanted to …
For the one who killed the child,
is himself dead.
The light …
- King Herod is dead.
- Is that true?
We're going home, Mary. Home to Nazareth.
(applause)
I have to be honest and say, -
- that I haven't prepared
any Christmas sermon.
(people murmur)
I don't know
if there are others who feel, -
- like some days
have disappeared.
As if time has flown by.
Strange.
My daughter said I should give
a sermon about trusting God.
I said it was too little.
And what does that have to do
with Jesus' birth and Christmas?
So stupidly I answered this morning.
Because in reality, that's probably what
it's all about.
We must trust in God.
Even if it doesn't always feel
like he's here with us.
Things happen as they happen.
I'm unprepared,
and you really must excuse that.
But I can't
move Christmas to tomorrow.
And I'm damn well forced to
stand here and look you all in the eyes, -
- because I chose it myself.
But there's one thing that helps me.
And that's that I trust in God.
Just like Mary had to trust in God, -
- when an angel came and said
that she would give birth to God's son.
And Joseph had to, when he was to
take care of a child that wasn't his.
And as Jesus had to trust in God
when he discovered, -
- that his task here on earth
was inhumanly hard.
We celebrate Christmas, -
- because God's son was born
here on earth as a human.
Can we trust that?
If we believe it, then it's true.
And if we don't believe it, -
- it might still be true.
(church organ plays)
Merry Christmas.
Yes, I just want to say
that it was a very beautiful sermon.
- Thank you very much.
- I'm looking forward to coming again.
- Have you seen Oskar?
- He was standing right over there earlier.
- No, I think he's gone home.
Is that him?
- Is there something you want to say to him?
- No.
- Well, but Merry Christmas.
- Happy birthday.
- Merry Christmas, everyone.
— Thanks.
- Did you find Oskar?
- No.
- Won't you see him over Christmas break?
- Yeah, but it's just not the same.
I thought he would wait for me.
Remember, Josefine:
Love is patient.
Can you have a Merry Christmas
and a really happy birthday?
Thanks, same to you.
There you are. Aren't you coming home?
Yes,
You can't hang
all the elves on the same branch.
- Yes, so they can talk together.
- Then I'll hang the Christmas hearts here.
Then I can
put all the baubles right here.
Then the elves can talk to these.
How lovely they are.
How beautiful it is.
Now we're just missing one thing.
- And that's the gifts under the tree.
- The gifts!
— Yes, the gifts.
- I'd forgotten.
(sighs)
The gifts from Jesus.
- Are you okay?
- I'm wrapping gifts.
- Out, dad.
- Yes, of course.
A poor virgin sat in the barn.
Sat in the barn.
And bore Heaven's king son.
Hallelujah.
- We'll take them all together again.
- Next year, Lukas.
Now we're getting gifts.
This one's for you, Lukas.
This one's for you, mom.
And this one's for you, dad.
Oh, thanks.
- Look at this. A Kalaha game.
- How beautiful.
It's handmade.
Who made it?
Jesus, of course.
What is this now?
- No.
- How beautiful it is.
Uhm, how good it smells.
A thousand thanks.
It's a healing oil.
No, how beautiful it is.
I'm really happy with this one.
Thank you very much.
There are also some
who have a gift for you.
Today is Josefine's birthday,
hip hip hooray, hip hip hooray.
She surely gets a gift she wants,
that she's wished for this year, -
- with lovely chocolate and cakes too.
Long live Josefine:
Hip hip hooray!
Here you go. Happy birthday.
It's from all of us.
(murmuring)
That's Josefine right there.
- A thousand thanks.
- It was nothing.
(chimes)
I just need to fetch something.
- Jesus?
- Happy birthday.
Same to you.
And I think
you should give that to your dad.
He'll be really happy for it.
- It worked.
- What?
- Trusting in God.
- Of course.
Josefine?
- I'd better get going.
- It was nice seeing you.
I've figured out
how to close the time portal.
You just have to put it in the manger,
when I've left.
(chimes start)
Josefine, I'll never forget you.
Same to you.
- You have the house full of guests.
- I just had to find this one.
That's ...
- How ...
- It's a secret.
That's fantastic.
That's a miracle. Louise.
Just come in.
You promised to destroy the manger game.
It doesn't work anymore.
- There's something I want to ask you.
— Yes.
Maybe you'd like, you know,
to go out together or …
What about Emilie then?
She's been helping
to arrange all this.
She's the best friend.
But if you don't want to be boyfriend and girlfriend,
we can just be friends.
Josefine, sorry. Aren't you coming?
There's chips and soda.
We're coming now. Pine needles in the hair.
Josefine. Now it's party time.
Here ends our adventure
about Jesus and Josefine.
Josefine learned that there is something
more important than one's birthday.
Jesus learned that he is God's son,
and that great tasks await him.
Oskar got a girlfriend
and Jesper a cookbook.
Louise filled the church,
and Lukas got a Kalaha game.
We wish everyone
a merry and blessed Christmas -
- with lots of pine needles in the hair.
Jesus and Josefine
homeless heartache
but Jesus gets Josefine
to believe in miracles
Jesus and Josefine
faithless time machine
tempter's concubine
she needs miracles
when she wavers
Danish lyrics:
Scandinavian Text Service